[music]
Hey.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat.
Heat. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome back to the Ask Abijit Show
episode 324. for today. I hope you're
all doing great and I'm going to take
questions about geopolitics and history
that you have asked in the comments.
Before we get to that, let's see who is
there on the live chat. Let me greet
some of you. I can see geopolitical
Dubai is here. Geopolitical Dubai is
here from Indor. Good evening. Good
evening, sir. BSVS is back. The Dark
Knight will return Ram G and thank you
so much for once again gifting
memberships. So very kind of you sir.
Thank you very much indeed. Satellite is
here. Well, satellite has an interesting
prefix but all right satellite
[laughter]
um uh Utkar Shukla geopolitical once
again Gajjapati Dave Madhav Gupta rude
sniper Gajjapati Dv Madav Gupta rude
sniper who else do we have Reika Jar Ram
GI Vidhiar good evening ma'am good to
see you Kiki Susant Ola Seenor Hola Abu
Singh uh Aayush Singh Pranam Pranam G
who Um Nabita Das good evening Hers 009
surprise surprise indeed. Swami Hers
Krishna of the Surinab Netherlands good
evening and good day to you sir. Um
Mahita Bushetti helloar Mahadev indeed
Abishek Shuklas says 99 earthquakes in
Iran.
Really? That's interesting. Uh I'll I'll
see that if that's the case. Okay. Sumit
good evening from Jaipur. Good evening
to you. real puddin jaram gi puddin 444
good evening rahul dunak hello good to
see you sir swami is here from Jaipur
hello mama bucket VFX welcome back uh
Nagarandanda Shenoi uh namaskaram gi
happy Saturday to you as well yes hello
uh Mahabushi once again Mac 4 J1U
Manhattan I6Wishek
Shukla Death Ray 9 Alvin Rodriguez hello
indeed
Uh Hijakh Dask Gupta hello Shivasai good
to see you. Brave robot is here says
meow. All right. Raguir Soleni is here
from Vadudra. Good evening sir. Uh
Nikesh Dahal Namaste GI Rituij Baradwaj
Panam G. Um
Kamill Parasar is here from Meritt Up.
Merritt Meritt up. Good evening sir.
Thank you so much. Harsh. Uh Bandikar
Bhoji. Namaskar G akshai Lo lo Sar good
evening um pranav 581 Manhattan action
4216 evening Roshan Mea hello Roshan Mha
is watching from LinkedIn
Shanai is here from Hyderabad Ashini Dax
Dak 1894 Ram Ram G Pratik Vora Nirvana
Shanks good evening good evening
Manisharu namaste G namaste bandar Bji
harsh jay goan sal indeed
Mlavin. Hello Mlavven G. Nikesh Dahal
Bandakar Baji and Mama Bak Baket VFX
greetings soldier boy salute. Putin from
Hyderabad Panchchar
4161. God bless DJT. All right. God
bless DJT. Uncertainty principal is also
here. Who else do we have? Ankita Kachab
G. Namaste G. Namaste indeed. Uh
Mahabusetti is an Indian in London.
Well, good afternoon to you, madam.
Blastor. Blast is here. Who else? Rahul
Dun. Uh, fun for fun for play free fire
581. Humanity survives. I hope it does.
Ritu Badwajri
K9X Empire 7 Nirvana Shanks. Good
evening once again. Chandi Priya,
Namaste G. Namaste indeed. Brianka
saywas good evening mo [laughter]
and everyone else. Okay I could go on
doing this forever but let me end that
here. Good evening to all of you. Good
day to all of you wherever you are
depending on where you are. And with
that let's get going with some
questions. What are the questions do we
have? Okay we'll first discuss
geopolitics and then move into history.
So this is we're going to start with
geopolitics questions. Real Vader
Buddhin says there's news coming about a
trade deal between the EU, European
Union and India. But EU is a US vasal
and the US today is acting like an
imperial power. Shouldn't it arm twist
the EU? So will the United States arm
twist the European Union to not sign a
trade deal with India?
That's an interesting question. So uh
uh there have been you know uh
statements coming out coming out from
the EU from uh Madame Usula Vanderlayin
the president of the EU and Madame Kaya
Kalas who is like the foreign minister
of the EU that sort of thing and they
have both said that you know Madame Rula
Fondonder is visiting India in a couple
of days uh for the 26th of January uh
event and uh most likely
there will be progress on a trade deal
between India and the EU. Maybe even a
signing of the trade deal between India
and the EU when she is here when she's
in India and it's been described by the
EU as the mother of all deals, you know.
So that could be a significant uh
gamecher potentially. I don't use the
word gamecher very often but it could
turn out to be a gamecher economically
for India and the EU, right? potentially
depending on the parameters of the deal
and the way it's being described by the
EU leadership as the mother of all deals
sounds like a big deal for sure, right?
Uh and of course we know that the EU is
under tremendous pressure from the
United States. The US is not just
pressurizing nations like India and
China and Russia. It's pressurizing its
own allies, its own assets, its own
vascals. Right? Trump has threatened
various tariffs on the EU nations uh
about Greenland and then he has walked
back on that threat and so on. So Trump
is a mercurial figure. He's going to
threaten everybody. He he has no issue
no problem imposing massive tariffs on
European nations. He threatened Mr. Mak
of France with 200% tariffs on champagne
and wines and whatnot. Uh so you never
know what the US is going to do with its
own allies. it's no longer acting like a
friendly power with its allies, with its
vasals.
Um, so in this kind of a climate,
geopolitical climate where you not, we
don't know what's going to happen, where
the US is acting like like an openly
imperial power like you say it makes
sense for the EU to hedge its bets and
you know make deals with nations like
India, China and China. Maybe not Russia
but definitely India and China. India
has a massive market. India has a lot to
offer. uh so the EU would certainly
benefit from a trade deal with India. So
it's it's kind of depending on how the
trade deal is structured, it could be a
massively beneficial deal for both both
the both the EU and for India, mutually
beneficial, right? Um and we know that
the EU is a bunch a group of nations
that for all intents and purposes are
American bas.
So what happens? Will the US pressurize
the EU into uh not signing this trade
deal? I think the US is not in a
situation where it can do that right. I
mean, what's it going to threaten the EU
with? A military invasion, tariffs.
Don't sign a deal with India or I'll
tariff you to hell.
So, most likely the trade deal will
happen. Looks like the way the
pronouncements are being made, it looks
like it's kind of almost almost settled,
you know, the parameters of the deal.
That's how it sounds like. So, let's
wait and watch a couple of days. I think
the US will not be able to arm twist the
EU into not signing a trade deal with
India. Looks like it's almost done, but
who knows? You never know. So, I think
we're going to have to wait and watch
next couple of days, next two, three
days, see what happens. Most likely the
trade deal will be signed. If not then
it's if the US somehow manages
to prevent the signing of a trade deal
between between India and the EU that
would be a very massively hostile act
against India and against the EU both
right um so let's see let's wait and
watch it's going to be a couple of days
I expect that the e the trade deal will
get signed of course uh if that happens
it benefits the EU it benefits India as
And it kind of reduces the effect that
American tariffs and threats and arm
twisting will have on the EU and on
India also. Right? See the US has
essentially priced India out of its
market. The US has uh imposed what 50%
tariffs right now on India. And if you
are an Indian business, okay, let's say
you are an Indian business owner and
let's say you are you are exporting
something to the US.
Let's say you're exporting hats to the
US. Just a very random example. Let's
say you're exporting cowboy hats to the
US, okay? And you can manufacture cowboy
hats and sell them to the to to a US
company at a very uh relatively cheap
price. So let's say a cowboy hat is sold
for $100 in the US. But I can let's say
if you but if you're producing if you're
producing them in India, you're going to
be able to produce them for let's say
$10 and you sell the hats to the
American company at $20 a piece, then
they're going to sell it to their
customers at $80 a piece.
All right? But if the tariffs are 50%,
then you know uh they're going to have
to pay pay 50% of what they are paying
to you to the US government. So, they're
going to pay you 20, they're going to
pay 10 to the US government and then
they can only have the remaining $70
instead of $80. Maybe not a great
example. Maybe you're selling something
for $50.
They're going to sell it for $80. But
now it becomes 75 because they have to
pay 25 more and that that makes it
commercially unviable for them. So, what
happens is that if you are in this
business of exporting stuff to the US,
then you will stop getting orders,
you'll stop getting contracts, right?
And that's what's hitting so many Indian
businesses right now because American
partners are kind of wary of buying
things from India because who knows what
tariffs Trump will impose. He's talking
about 500% tariffs also. You know that
sort of threat if India keeps buying
Russian oil. So India is getting pushed
out of the American market by Trump. So
makes sense to export to the EU, right?
Um so that's why it could be a win-win
thing for India and the EU. And
obviously that Trump will not be pleased
if this happens. So maybe he may he may
try to interfere but u I expect he may
not succeed. So let's wait and watch a
couple of days two three days and let's
see what uh what's the outcome of uh the
visit of the EU leadership to India
which begins the next couple of days.
Let's wait and watch. I expect it most
likely it'll the trade deal will get
will get done.
Okay this is about India and the UAE.
Brian Kasikar Biswar says, "Is the
sudden India UAE defense pact aimed at
counterbalancing a potential Pakistan
Saudi security arrangement or is there a
deeper strategic calculation at play? If
the US if the UAE already enjoys robust
US defense backing, why seek India at
all?" Susworth AI says, "What do you
make out of the negotiations on the on
the defense pact of India and the UAE?
Is it in India's national interest
because we wouldn't want our military to
be engaged in other problems? Is the US
pressurizing India to form a defense
pact with the UAE which is a US vasile?
Would this prove to be detrimental to
our sovereignty? Rishabar says recently
Mr. Muhammad bin Zed visited Delhi the
the leader of the UAE and met with Prime
Minister Modi. A very brief visit right
but he met with Prime Minister Modi. The
FDA free trade agreement was expanded
and the new target is to make is to make
trade $200 billion by 2030 or so. also
over foreign secretary Vikram Nissri
talked about a major defense deal and
there's news of deals of an L LNG
liqufied natural gas deal and a gold
deal as well. What exactly is cooking?
How do you see it as India's expanding
role in the Middle East as well as in
the context of the Muhammad bin Salman
versus Muhammad bin Zed feud in Yemen
and Saudi Pakistan pact? Okay, a lot is
going on but there is talk of a US of of
a India UAE defense agreement which is
rather unusual right
so we have excellent relations with the
UAE no question about that now the
question that's being asked over here
primarily is under the assumption that
the UAE is a US asset a US uh
uh
you know a US was
So UAE yeah sashwhat aims says UAE is a
US. Is it really US wasal?
The way if you properly look at and
analyze the the you know the
relationships and alignments in West
Asia or the Middle East like we call it,
you will say that the UA is more aligned
with Israel than the US.
The UA's primary partner in the region
or ally if you want to call it an ally
in the region is Israel not the United
States. Okay. Saudi Arabia you could say
is an asset or an ally or a vasal
whatever you want to call it of the US.
But Saudi Arabia has been playing an
interesting game. It's been exporting
obviously it's it's a major oil
exporter. has been exporting oil to
China and taking payment in Chinese yuan
bypassing the US dollar which is very
naughty. The US won't like it and Saudi
Arabia doesn't have that great of a
relationship with Israel the kind of
relationship that UAE has with Israel.
So it's Saudi Arabia US but Saudi Arabia
is also flirting with China so to say.
Okay. It's not staying completely loyal
to the US. It's also playing a game with
China under the table perhaps maybe
actually not under the table quite
openly and then you have the UAE which
is strongly aligned with Israel and UAE
is also now aligning aligning itself
with India and Pakistan and Saudi Arabia
are have this mutual defense agreement
which they signed a few months ago right
so Saudi Arabia is
is playing games with China and it's
taking Pakistani help to secure maybe a
nuclear umbrella or something. Okay. And
there's the Turkey angle as well. So,
it's Turkey, Saudi Arabia,
and China. And Saudi Arabia has also
acquired Pakistani military support.
So, so it's Turkey, Saudi Arabia, China,
Pakistan. Even though Pakistan is no
longer a Chinese vasal, it's an American
vasal. It's kind of a complicated game
here. So Pakistan and China they are no
longer on the same page except when it
comes to India.
So Saudi Arabia is essentially playing
games that are you can say say are
anti-India games for its own reasons.
It's it maybe India is not the central
issue when it comes to Saudi Arabia's
strategic calculations
but it makes sense for them to perhaps
you know acquire the Pakistani uh
nuclear umbrella which obviously once
again Pakistani nuclear umbrella means
American nuclear umbrella actually okay
so because the Pakistani nukes are most
likely American nukes on loan most
likely 99%. So that's the game. So on
the other side we have Israel,
UAE and India.
Okay. And India and the UAE UAE have
excellent relations. I mean if you look
at the population of the UAE it's like
60% people from the subcontinent at
least 40% from India. So 40% of of the
population in the UAE is Indians. Not
citizens but population.
Um
so there is that. So uh and you know
what the UAE would very much like to be
you know like to have you could say
military protection from India. They
would very much like to have it. I mean
I don't know what's going on in the
minds of the leadership. Of course I'm
not privy to those thoughts but it makes
sense for the UAE to instead of
depending on certain nations depend on
India to a certain extent and Israel to
another extent.
So that is the deal and obviously there
is a UAE Saudi Arabia rivalry that is
now kind of a little more in the open
but it's been there for a long time.
Um so I would not really consider see
UAE is obviously acquiring purchasing
American weapons and all but I don't
really consider the UAE to be completely
a US vasal. The UAE is more aligned with
Israel when Israel is a special nation.
It's not a US facade, right? It is not.
Israel is a special nation. So that is
the thing. So uh
so that's that that that is the issue.
That is the deal. Saudi Arabia and the
UAE have a rivalry for primacy in the
region. There's a rivalry that's that's
that extends to regions like Yemen. It
extends to the Horn of Africa.
uh
maybe Sudan, maybe Somalia, definitely
Somali land and uh Eritria, all of that.
There's Libya also and that's a long
long long story there. But there is a
definite Saudi Arabia UAE rivalry. Saudi
Arabia is aligning with Pakistan and
uh Turkey and the UAE is aligning itself
with Israel and the UAE. So u overall I
think it's good for India. it will not u
so the question the the concern over
here that I I'm seeing is will this be
detrimental to India's sovereignty right
um it will not be detrimental to India's
sovereignty
that see how do you how does sovereignty
get jeopardized sovereignty gets
jeopardized if someone else is in full
or partial control of your territorial
integrity of your borders which is not
the case or if somebody is in full or
partial control of your economy that's
not the case or if somebody is in full
or partial control of your military
which is not the case right so in no way
does India's sovereignty get impacted by
this maybe we are extending some
protection potentially I don't it
depends on what kind of deal is signed
but maybe it will mean that we will
extend our protection military
protection to the UAE which does not in
any shape or form impact India's
sovereignty or is it's not in any shape
or form detrimental to India's
sovereignty. So, so what's cooking?
There's a lot that's cooking.
Apparently, the FDA free trade agreement
between India and UAE has been expanded.
There's a more ambitious target by 2030
or so. Major defense deal potentially.
I'm not sure if it's been signed or what
the parameters are but major defense
deal you know um defense agreement which
could essentially make India and the UE
allies which India doesn't really do but
here we have it looks like that and
energy deal gold also potentially so
India's role is definitely expanding in
the Middle East and it's expanding in
the context of the UAE and Israel
there's a silent actor here which is
Israel okay so that's the deal
okay greenland Let's discuss Greenland.
Will Europe fall to the US on Greenland?
What's the future of NATO? That's what I
don't lie says. Asks Mr. Karat says why
has Trump bowed to Europe on Greenland?
Was European unity too much for the US?
So, will Europe fold to the US on
Greenland? Second question is why has
Trump folded to Europe on Greenland? And
Aayush says why has Trump let go of the
talk of Greenland to which he was saying
that the US needs somehow anyhow
possible any backdoor backroom deal
happened. What's in my opinion? Okay. So
a couple of days ago, few days ago,
three four days ago, Trump uh said that
you know he would impose what 10% 25%
tariffs on certain NATO nations Denmark
etc.
uh and that would increase to 25% in a
few months and remain in place as long
as Greenland is not solved. And what's
the solution he wants? He wants US
sovereignty over Greenland. He says that
you know what we already have our
military in place in Greenland. We
already have a military base in
Greenland. And it's not like Greenland
is Danish territory. You had a few boats
come there a few few centuries ago. We
also had boats coming in there, right?
And Denmark is sovereignty. It's it's
not something on paper, right? If you
you if you have sovereignty over a
region, you must be in a position to to
hold it and defend it. And Denmark is
not in a position to do that. So Trump
says that that that's why you need to
reach an agreement uh with us, the US on
Greenland. We'll pay you some money and
you hand over sovereignty to us and we
need it for national security reasons.
We want to keep Russia out and China out
and etc etc. Obviously there's um the
question of um you know very important
thing which is resources, oil, gas,
minerals and so on. So Trump wants
greenland.
Now Trump says more recently that you
know those tariffs will not be applied.
So what does it mean? Does it mean that
Trump has given up on Greenland?
Will he simply be content with America
having the US having a few more bases or
or or a more augmented military presence
in Greenland with sovereignty still
remaining in the hands of Denmark?
What's the deal actually? Right. So, who
has folded? Is Europe going to fold to
to the US or is Trump folding and bowing
to Europe? What's the deal? Neione of
these things. So, Trump is not bowing to
Europe. He's not folding to Europe. And
uh what I expect is most likely in the
coming days, weeks or months, some kind
of agreement will be reached. Um and it
will what kind of agreement will it be?
It will be either full sovereignty for
the US or de facto sovereignty for the
US. See you can do something you can
achieve an objective without
without making it very obvious. So the
US already has a military presence in
Greenland. Let's say they expand
military presence in Greenland. Maybe
they reach an agreement with Denmark
that instead of one military base, we
will have seven military bases in
Greenland. Okay. But technically the
sovereignty remains in the hands of
Denmark. Technically on paper it may be
Danish territory but if the US military
has seven let's say bases hypothetically
on Greenland does it really mean that
Greenland is Danish territory anymore? I
mean Japan is technically a sovereign
nation but it has 130 plus US military
bases. You call that sovereignty right?
The real who really controls Japan owns
Japan occupies Japan is the US. Japan is
not a so sovereign nation.
Similarly they could do the same thing
in Greenland. So technically it remains
Danish territory on paper but for all
intents and purposes on the ground it's
the Americans who own and operate it. So
technically so that satisfies um the the
honor of Denmark that you know what we
were able to stand firm and we did not
give up our sovereignty. But look what's
happening there. It's all Americans.
[laughter]
So the sovereignty is just technical.
It's just on paper. So either the US
will take full sovereignty
of Greenland or it will achieve de facto
ownership and possession of Greenland.
Both ways the US wins and Trump wins.
Okay. But if the Americans take full
sovereignty of of Greenland, then it's
kind of a slap in the face to Denmark,
right? Kind of. And if they take def
facto sovereignty without actually
changing sovereignty on paper then
Denmark's honor and and and you know
Denmark saves face but knowing Trump I
expect that he will want actual full
possession sovereign possession of
Greenland because he wants he wants to
be remembered as one of the greatest
presidents of all time in the US right
and the greatest presidents are those
who expand territory
right so I expect that he wants to be
remembered as the president who who
expanded American territory and acquired
a major new possession, Greenland.
So, I expect that's that's what he's
going to go after
uh eventually. I expect that's what's
going to happen. If not, it's going to
be anyway de facto
ownership of Greenland.
So, either way, the US wins and they get
what they want.
Brianka Biswaris says, "Why is Russia
seemingly backing the US on Greenland
issue despite harming its own Arctic
interests? Is this to weaken NATO or is
there a deeper strategic tradeoff? Is
there a deeper strategic trade-off? Is
there some kind of backdoor back back
room agreement behind the scenes
agreement with the US? What's what's the
deal?" So, if you see the recent
statements of uh Mr. Putin or on
Greenland. He is, you could say, backing
the American position on Greenland. But
Denmark doesn't really, you know, have
any right to own Greenland and
historical reasons and so on. And Danish
sovereignty is just technical. It's only
on paper. It doesn't really have
sovereignty and it doesn't have any
historical justification for owning
Greenland. You never had Danish people
who lived on Greenland. It was
discovered by
by by Le Ericson, wasn't it? Le F E F E
F E F E F E F E F E F E F E F Een Eric
the Red Le F E F E F E F E F E F E F E F
E F E F Erikson about a thousand years
ago and it was a white land but he was a
good salesman so he called it green land
and that's why you had a few Danish
boats going there and you know temporary
occupation of some little coastal parts
of Greenland that sort of thing and
that's how it became technically Danish
territory. Denmark is not a military
militarily powerful nation or whatever.
So Putin is laying all that out and
saying that you know Denmark doesn't
really have a case for owning Greenland.
That's what he is saying. Now, why is he
doing this? If the Americans take
control of Greenland, it does uh harm
Russia's interests in the region, Arctic
interests. Um, since we're discussing
Greenland, we might as well go to the
map, right?
Okay. So, let's bring out the map and we
are talking about Greenland. Okay. If
you ever travel from let's say the UK or
Europe to the US or North America, you
will most likely fly over Greenland.
Also, Iceland. So Greenland, it looks
big, but it's not that big. Okay, but
it's pretty, it's obviously a
substantial territory. So it's kind of
from this perspective, it's kind of
between Russia and North America
clearly. So it so you can see why the
Americans want it, right? Um
so so why is Putin doing this is the is
the big question. Is he really uh I mean
the Russians have a major you know
interest in the Arctic region because
they are an Arctic nation and much of
their shipping etc passes through the
Arctic region and shipping and energy
and and fishery operations and and
military operations submarines and
warships and whatnot. I mean it's it's
critical for Russia. So why is Trump I
mean why is Putin seemingly supporting
the US on Greenland and not Denmark?
Well, Mr. Putin is being practical.
The US anyway has a presence in
Greenland, military presence. They have
tool base or whatever it is, right? And
there is absolutely nothing Denmark can
do to prevent the Americans from just
walking in and taking the territory.
There's nothing Denmark can do, right?
So Putin knows that it's essentially a
done deal. A feta compli knows it's a
done deal. He is a sensible person. He's
a practical person, pragmatic person. He
knows a done deal when he sees it. The
Americans are not going to take are
going to take Greenland. You can take it
from me in writing. The Americans are
going to one way or the other have
Greenland.
So what Putin is doing is creating
divisions within NATO.
Okay, that's what Russia is doing. They
are playing various NATO members against
each other with the hope of creating
divisions and ruptures within NATO
itself. See, Denmark obviously is deeply
offended. So, so are many other EU
nations or NATO nations. They are deeply
offended that you are supposed to be the
the protector and the benevolent leader
of NATO and now you're targeting your
own people and you just because you're
powerful, you just want to grab
territory like we have by like we
Europeans have been doing in Asia and
Africa for centuries. Now you're doing
that against us.
How can you have such double standards?
We are white people. We Europeans. you
can't colonize us. You can't bully us in
that manner the way we have been
bullying the the the the the [laughter]
non-white people. How can you do that to
us? So, they're outraged.
They're outraged. And Putin naturally
will want to, you know, uh exacerbate
those divisions that have crept in crept
into NATO. So, that's the game. And by
that also kind of kind of you know if if
there are divisions within NATO if the
EU nations are unhappy if NATO members
are unhappy if the European members of
NATO are unhappy with the overall bully
hedgemen the US then it can have an
effect on the Ukraine war effort also
right
maybe they will lose they will maybe
they will lose the morale that's needed
to sustain the the Ukraine war effort
and keep on replenishing Ukraine and
supporting Zalinski Right? Maybe they
lose the motivation. Maybe the
motivation may decrease by 15, 20, 25
percentage points. That method helps. So
that's the that's the deal. Russia knows
the US
it's a done deal. They're going to take
Greenland one way or the other. Either
full sovereignty or de facto
sovereignty, but they're going to have
Greenland one way or the other. So just
accept what's in inevitable and take
advantage of it in some way or some
shape or form. And that's what the
Russians are doing. That's the deal.
It's not like
it's not like Russia is going to send
armed force its armed forces to help the
US take Greenland. It's not like that.
It's just, you know, it's like it's like
sledging in cricket.
Okay? You got two batsmen who are
batting. You know that they have some
tensions between them, some kind of
rivalry. Okay? So, as the as the
fielding side, you're going to put
things in their ears to create tensions
between them. maybe run out or whatever
or maybe they'll play a rash shot or
something, right? That's sledging. So
that's what Putin is doing. He's
sledging.
He's trying to create he's trying to do
mental disintegration like Steve Voy
used to do. That's the game. And when
Mr. Putin does that and says that people
pay attention, right?
So that's what's being done there.
[snorts] Okay.
Manka says, "What's your view on Trump's
board of peace? Will it eventually
replace the UN and should India join it?
Rushab says what is the Gaza peace
board? Trump invited Vladir Putin,
Shabbaz Sharif and Prime Minister Modi
amongst many others in the board amongst
many others. Once again, no China in the
board, not in Israel and the $1 billion
fee for permanent membership. Is the US
now discarding the old things and
forming new ones? Should India sit in
this board as a full member just test
waters and silently pull back? particip
participate for Kurtsy and quietly
withdraw or completely reject and ignore
Donald J. Trump's offer. Okay. Board of
Peace, Gaza Board of Peace. Let's first
find out who are the members so far thus
far. Okay. Um, which nations
have joined Trump's
Board of Peace?
Okay. Which countries? Which countries?
Full list of countries.
News Nation here the countries two days
ago we do we have something more recent
one day ago
um we'll not go into the analysis
who do we have okay the following
countries have signed on Bahrain Morocco
Argentina Armenia Azarbaijan
Armenia Belgium Bulgaria Egypt Hungary
Indonesia Jordan Kazakhstan Kosovo
Mongolia Pakistan Paraguay Qatar Saudi
Arabia Turkey UAE Usbakistan.
So no major nation has has joined
Trump's border of peace. Uh you have
Pakistan.
I mean you have a bunch of very
disparate nations that don't seem to
have much in common except that they all
want to be on the on Trump's good side
kind of you know that sort of thing. So
that's the Gaza Board of Peace and Trump
says that if you pay a billion dollars
you can become a permanent member. But
who's going to be the chairman of the
board of peace? It's going to be Trump
and Trump is going to be the guy with
the veto. one person has a veto and he
decides what happens and he can even
eject nations from membership if he
feels like if they if they displease him
in some way. So this is I mean what is
this
right and and and is Trump trying to u
you know replace the UN security council
the United Nations by creating this
thing
one wonders right so that's his board of
peace it's a bunch of nations who are
essentially sucking up to Mr. Trump,
right? Um, not trying to be
disrespectful. I'm just saying that's
what they're doing. Um, they want to be
on his good side and and that's the
deal. So, what do you get if you are on
the board of peace? So, the board of
peace is about Gaza, right? These
nations will oversee what happens in
Gaza and ensure that everything is done
properly, blah blah blah, all that
stuff. Gaza,
how does it tie into India's national
interest? ensuring that things are done
properly as per Trump's plan on in Gaza.
What does it have to do with us and our
national interest? Essentially nothing.
And if we are on the board of peace and
you go to the summit,
okay, let's say prime minister, let's
say hypothetically India joins the board
of peace and India is then required to
participate in the summit yearly summit
or whatever it is that Trump has called.
Trump summons everybody, everybody in
the board of peace, come meet, come to
so and so place and I shall oversee the
next meeting. So Mr. Modi has to go and
know whether Trump you know whether
Shabbah Sharif is going to be there and
Trump is then going to bring them
together and do a photo opportunity and
maybe uh try and do some deal between
Indian Pakistan. Do we want to be in
that situation?
Do we want to be in the situation where
we have to be in the same where our
prime minister has to be in the same
room as Shabbash Sharif and Trump is the
guy the big guy the boss who's going to
tell everyone what to do and he's going
to have Shabba Sharif come and miss meet
Mr. Modi and he will insist that you
guys shake hands and so on for the
cameras. Is that what we want to be put
through? I don't think so. Trump is
going to do such things and then he's
going to claim that you know I I u
brought forth peace between India and
Pakistan. I first ended the the
operation Zindur three-day war and now
see I made them shake hands and he will
take credit for this and then he will
say now I definitely deserve the Nobel
Peace Prize. Do we want to be part of
Trump's games? Do we want to be part of
Shri Donald J. Trump's circus? I don't
think so.
In my opinion, India should stay away
from this board of peace. In my opinion,
Prime Minister Modi should not
be in the same room as either Shabbash
Sharif or even Donald J. Trump for the
foreseeable future.
So, I completely
would say I would say that India should
just stay out of this matter. Don't
accept this. Don't reject it. Just don't
comment on this. Don't talk about the
board of peace. Ignore it.
That's what India should do. That is the
correct strategy for India.
If you become if you become a member of
that that board, it's it's going to be
used in some way or the other to
pressure India more and to create
embarrassing situations for Prime
Minister Modi
and
thereby for India. So, India should stay
out of the border of peace. We should
neither accept nor reject. Just stay out
of it. Ignore this entire matter as if
it doesn't exist. Okay, that's what we
should do.
Ashish
Ashish says, uh, Finland president
confirmed what you have always been
saying about F-35s. Mark Carney also
said something about rules-based world
order that I've been speaking about.
What has changed this much that the West
is now openly berating the USA? Has the
world crossed some point of no return?
No. See, what's changed is that what
used to happen behind the scenes that I
had to explain and people would not
believe is now happening in the open. So
everything I used to say is now everyone
can see it happening right now. F-35s,
let's talk about F-35s. What have what
have I been saying about F-35s? I have
been saying that if you are a country
that has bought an F-35 or a bunch of
F-35s and you want to operate the F-35.
Let's say you wake up in the morning,
your pilot wants to go and take the F-35
for a spin in the sky, you're going to
have to
ask for an OTP for the Americans.
[clears throat]
You have to send a request for OTP.
Today's OTP for to get an OTP, you have
to first input the entire flight plan.
what you plan to do, what uh what flight
plan means what areas or what regions
will you fly or fly, what weapons are
you planning to use [snorts] and so on.
You have to give the detailed flight
plan. How many hours are you planning to
fly? How many sorties and so on and then
it goes to the US and they examine
everything and if they deem that it is
acceptable then they're going to send
you an OTP. Once you get the OTP, you
input the OTP in the F35's computer and
then the F35 starts up.
Okay. And then if you while flying if
you deviate from the fight flight plan
then the weapon system shut down and it
becomes just a flying bird.
Okay. And let's say you input a
fightlight plan that you know I'm plan
to take off with my F-35 and I'm going
to bomb Pakistan and come back. You will
not get an OTP. Denied. That's what I
have been saying. I have also been
saying that the Americans can remotely
disable weapon systems. Okay. Kill
switches. They have kill switches
and they will also have back doors in in
the F-35 systems. So they will know
exactly what you're doing probably in
real time. That's what I have been
saying.
And now the president of Finland has
confirmed what I have been saying that
they can't even use the F-35s without
American permission. Essentially that's
what it means. I have been saying this
for years.
And there's been a lot of skepticism
from various people about what I've been
saying and so on. Right. Well, here we
are. The president of Finland has
confirmed this. So, here we are. Mark
Carney also said something about the
rules-based world order that it's a
whimsbased world order. Like I've been
saying, I'm not sure if he used the term
whimsbased world order, but that's
exactly what he means. So what Mark
Carney said essentially [laughter]
Mark Carney is very upset that the
Americans are that the US is pushing
the European nations and the NATO
nations around like a bully pushes
around a bunch of school kids, right?
The same way the European nations have
been treating the third world until now.
So he's essentially upset that the US is
treating NATO and EU the way NATO and EU
countries used to treat the third world
countries. So you are you have now
demoted us to the category of third
world nations and you're treating us
like them. That's what that's what he
he's upset about, right? Double
standards.
The first world has always had double
standards towards so the so-called third
world, right? But now those double
standards are being applied by the US to
the first world nations. And that's what
Mark Carney is upset about.
How can you treat us the way we treat
the non-white nations? How can you do
that to us? It hurts our feelings. It
hurts our sentiments. That's what he's
complaining about. Mark Carney.
So essentially what Mark Carney is
saying is that there's no rules based
world order. There are double standards,
multiple set of standards. And now the
Americans are treating these nations,
Canada, EU nations with the same double
standards that they used to in the past
treat African and Asian nations. Yeah.
So what has changed? What's changed is
first of all
the double standards that was that were
applied to non-EU non-NATO nations are
now being applied by the Americans to
even the EU and NATO nations. They are
being bullied exactly the same way. that
has obviously hurt their precious
sentiments and feelings. It hurts. It
hurts. Yeah. Hurts my feelings.
Uh and secondly,
Trump is being completely open about
American imperialism. American
imperialism has always existed.
Nothing has changed, but it's now open.
It used to be done properly in the past
diplomatically.
Everything used to be done
diplomatically. Now there is no pretense
with Trump. He's not pretending.
He's open about American imperialism. So
these are the things that have changed.
So it's very clear now that the US is an
empire,
right? The US is not the benevalent
policemen of the world. The US is an
empire. It's going to extract its pound
of flesh from every nation. And the
nations that don't bend the knee,
they're going to be essentially squeezed
with tariffs and threats and what not.
So that's what's going on. That's what
has what has changed. The world has not
crossed some point of no return. The
world is changing.
Now the empire's imperialism is open is
is is open in the public. It's it's
there for everyone to see. Now no one
can mistake
it for anything else. It's open
imperialism.
So uh the world hasn't crossed some
point of no return. The world is
changing. It's changing rapidly. And
obviously these changes are many of
these changes are irreversible. Let's
say in four years or 3 years Trump um u
he deits office somebody else comes to
power. Does it mean the US will stop
behaving the way it's behaving like
right now? No. All the changes Trump
will make in the next three years
including the past one year what he's
done all of these are permanent changes.
So the world is changing and it's kind
of a permanent set of changes that's
coming in. Uh so it's not one point of
no return. It's just a journey of no
return that we are on
and that's what's changing and it's a
very rapid journey. uh the changes we'll
see geopolitically this this the next
five years uh they're going to exceed
essentially the changes that you see in
five decades so that's what we are
seeing right now
real Vladimir Putin says why does the US
wants to take over the Garcia islands
islands more directly what are the
benefits they get will it reduce Indian
naval influence in the region says your
views on Trump's recent statement on the
garia and the chos aripelago Could you
please provide a little background on
the deal and what exactly is the case?
Why is he suddenly calling out the UK
Maicius deal on these islands when it
was Donald Trump himself who had
supported it given that India was the
main broker of the deal and value of the
the value of the base? How should we
secure a strong foothold in the region
and prevent China from taking advantage
of it?
Okay. If you want to know about um the
Chaos Archipelago, the entire backstory
and so on, I have I have made a video on
this a few I don't know a year or so
ago. Um here we are. Let me see. Let's
go to my channel. Okay. And uh let's
remove this from here. Go to my channel.
Search for Chos.
Chos. And you will have this video. Uh
how the US and Britain stole Indian
Ocean Islands. Chos Archipelago that's
from a year or so ago in which I have
explained the whole matter in detail and
this video was then blatantly copied by
Von you know Von the news channel they
have something called gravitas or
something they they just copied the
video
uh so that's the if you want to
understand the background of the chaos
matter okay watch that video essentially
okay let's let's open the map and uh
where is map we're going to open the map
and first of all locate the trio was
archipelago.
So here is the map and we go to the
Indian Ocean region of our own backyard.
Uh we go south see we on the west coast
of India off the west coast of India we
have the lakshodep islands. Uh south of
that you have the Maldes which is part
of the same island chain and south of
that you have the so-called British
Indian Ocean territory which should
never belong to Britain because it has
no business being here but it belongs to
them and it's the southernmost part of
this uh entire island chain which starts
with the luxury and goes through the
Maldives and at the southernmost tip of
this island chain you have the so-called
British Indian Ocean Territory and the
Chaos Archipelago. It's a bunch of
islands over here. Okay. And the major
island here is this one here which they
call Diegoa.
If you look at the satellite image,
you'll find that there is a massive
American air base here. And you also
have uh naval facilities and uh
groundbased electroloptical deep space
surveillance and whatnot whatnot
whatnot. Okay. all kinds of uh signals
gathering u uh you know capabilities and
whatnot over here. So and this this
harbor that they have over here it can
very easily accommodate an entire
aircraft carrier. So it's a major naval
base and also a major air base and it's
also a major signals intelligence
gathering station and what and
everything. Massive presence they have
over here. I'll not go into the details
but you will see that this is a very
major base and this is a base from which
the Americans can project power across
the entire Indian Ocean region. They
acquired this air this this base thego
Garcia from the British I think a year
or two after
the 1971 war that India in which India
you know defeated Pakistan. So the
Americans wanted to prevent India from
defeating Pakistan and creating
Bangladesh and they sent an aircraft
carrier strike group into the Bay of
Bengal and the British also sent an
aircraft carrier strike group. So there
were two western aircraft carrier strike
groups in the Bay of Bengal but the
Russians the Soviets had sent a
submarine fleet nuclear submarines and
that's why the Americans and British
were not able to arm twist India and
that's why India was able to win the war
1971. So then the Americans realized
that we need a a base from which we can
project power in the Indian Ocean region
and it required you know bully India and
that's why they acquired uh the UGartha
from the British. Now the history of the
Ugaria is such that you know Britain has
no real sovereignty doesn't really have
any historical legitimacy or any
legitimate right over these islands. the
island should belong to Mauritius and
that's why the international court and
whatnot there's been proceedings and you
know the British had a couple of years
ago I think a year ago decided to uh
hand over sovereignty of the chos
archipelago to the to Maicius
okay
with the condition that the Americans
keep their lease on the Garcia for 99
years or something that sort of thing
but it will then technically be
sovereign Moraicious territory
And Trump doesn't like it. He says that
why is Britain doing this? We own
Britain. America, the Americans o
essentially own Britain. Britain is the
UK is an American vasal. We know that.
And as long as the Vasal owns the
territory, the Americans are fine. But
if you hand it over to Mauritius, then
it's a problem because Mauritius, well,
we don't have that sort of relationship
with Mauritius. And Trump says Mauritius
could even be a Chinese asset. That's
what what that's what Trump claims.
So if you look at the region, it's
India's backyard. India keeps claiming
right the Indian Ocean region is our
strategic backyard. That's slogan. So
it's part of our backyard and it's in
our backyard that the Americans have
this massive base from which they can
project power into India if required. H
and if you want to bomb Iran for
example, you take off from Diego Garcia.
Yeah. So it's a very major asset that
the Americans have Diego Garcia you know
air and naval base u so because the UK
has decided to hand over sovereignty to
Mauritius that's why Trump is upset
about this and it looks like the UK has
now decided to pause handing over
sovereignty to Mauritius let's see uh
what is the latest news on chaos let's
see
chaos
let's see news Trump forces British
Uturn UK withdraws she chosen bill.
Would you believe it? Trump forces
British U-turn with UK withdraws Chos
Island build about after UK US
president's great stupidity jar a year
year after the UK promised Borishes the
transfer of the entire Chos archipelago.
The UK appears to be backing out amid
backlash from Trump who called it a
stupid decision. The agreement was
signed in May 2025. It stated that that
sovereignty over the island would be
transferred to Mauritius who owns the
archipelago in accordance with the 2019
ruling of the international court of
justice but the UK would retain control
of the largest island the Garcia by
leasing it back for for a 99-year term
and Trump the Trump administration had
given it a green light at that time but
now Trump says it's a problem and it's
stupidity and so on and so forth. So
Trump is that sort of guy very
mercurial. He will change his tune on a
whim and everybody has to then scramble
to to please him. So the UK is now
scrambling to please him and it is
probably not going to transfer more
Morish the the sovereignty to Maicius
and maybe Trump will be happy with that
or maybe he will say that I want to buy
it from the UK. That also is a
possibility.
So that is the situation. Now the
question is will this reduce India's
naval influence in the region?
It's already reduced
right the Americans acquired Diego
Garcia in 1973 or whatever 1972 73 you
can look up the date and since then the
Americans have a major major power
projection base in the region right
India stays away from it
India the Indian Navy anyway doesn't
sail in that region where does the
Indian navy sail India has its own
strategic calculus, its own threat
perception. It stays away from the chos
archipelago.
Uh the furthest we will venture is uh
Maldives as and when required because
India has a neighbor neighborhood first
policy. So when there's a problem in the
Maldives of Storm or some issue then we
will go and help them out. That's all
we'll do. Um so the US anyway has
ownership of the Egaria. The actual
ownership is the UK. The UK has planned
to transfer ownership to Mauritius. Now
it is backing backtracking and saying it
will not do that. But the actual boots
on the ground and ownership of the
Gogaria that is the US. The US actually
operates the island. And if the UK
tomorrow says give it back to us, the US
has no obligation to give it back. Okay.
Possession is 9/10 of the law. The UK,
the US possesses the island physically.
It has God knows how many soldiers and
troops and personnel there.
So possession is essentially almost the
law. The Americans possess the island.
All this technicalities of transferring
sovereignty here and there that who
cares. What really matters is who
possesses the island physically. The
Americans possess it.
Um so India had insisted that India had
supported Mauritius in the matter and
now the UK is going to walk back on it.
What can India do about it? Absolutely
nothing. Absolutely nothing beyond
diplomatic pro protests or whatever. Uh
so how do we secure our strong foothold
in the region and prevent China from
taking advantage of it? There is no
China angle here at all whatsoever.
China has zero involvement in the Garcia
or the Chaos Archipelago. It's the US.
Okay. It's the US that owns it, operates
it and and that's that's the thing.
Okay. Next question.
Anamay Khan says, "Do you think Prime
Minister Modi will now avoid going to
the US or any of its vasals till the end
of
his tenure, Trump's tenure? Given
America's hostility towards India and
also recently an ex US military officer
Terren Jackson was reportedly sent to
assassinate Mr. Modi since if he goes if
he does go at Gore for God forbid
something happens to him there India
unfortunately can't do a thing given the
difference in our military economic
capabilities we don't want to repeat
what happened in 1965 what happened in '
what happened was it prime minister
Shastri 1965
probably
okay
I don't think Mr. Modi is going to the
US anytime soon I don't think Mr. Modi
is going to meet Mr. Trump anytime soon.
Mr. Trump has this hab habit of
humiliating people.
You can see it over and over again. He
he does that even when the person isn't
there. I mean, see the way Mr. Trump has
been speaking about Mr. Mako, the French
president. He's been taunting, insulting
Mr. Macron for a long time, Mr. Trump,
hasn't he? Even recently in Davo, he did
that. Even Mr. Carney, right?
So Mr. Modi, it doesn't make any sense
for Mr. Modi to visit the US anytime
soon or to even be in the same place
where Mr. Trump is anytime soon. So I
don't see Mr. Modi visiting the US
probably as long as Mr. Trump is
president unless something changes
drastically. Any of its vasals that's a
different story. Um
the US has a very large number of
vasals. All the EU nations, all the NATO
nations, UK, Canada, all the Western
European nations, even Japan, South
Korea and so on and various other
nations that I will not name here. Does
it mean that Mr. Modi should not visit
any of them? That's not quite the case.
I think Mr. Modi will definitely avoid
the US and being in the same place where
M where Mr. Trump is. Um, vasal
countries, I'm sure Mr. Modi can visit
the UK or various European nations even
Japan, South Korea, whatever depending
on whether it's required needed or not.
Uh when it comes to this assassination
matter,
uh there have been reports that some
fellow called Terren Jackson was
reportedly sent to assassinate Mr. Modi.
What's what's the
evidence for that?
There's no evidence for it. It doesn't
mean that this this did not happen. My
point is there is no evidence that backs
up this this speculation. This is pure
speculation in the absence of any actual
hard evidence. Right? It's speculation.
I mean some people are claiming this
happened that happened. On what basis
are you claiming it? Oh, we have
intelligence. We have we've got this
report from somewhere. We have sources.
That's not hard evidence that you can
you know that is that will stand
scrutiny in a court of law. It's not
that sort of evidence. Right? So it's
speculation. So I am going to there's
even been speculation that when Mr. Modi
went for the for the SEO summit where he
met with with Mr. Putin and Mr. Xiinping
at that time also Mr. Putin had taken
Mr. Modi on a on a car ride for 45
minutes to maybe discuss something in
private and some people were speculating
maybe there was an assassin
assassination attempt there too that Mr.
Put in prevented. Uh what's the truth
behind that? I don't know. Okay. The
Russians have made no statements about
any such thing. So it's pure
speculation.
But obviously it doesn't mean that there
is no risk to Mr. Bodh's life. He has to
be obviously very careful. He can't just
randomly visit some country just like
that. And whenever he does visit some
country, the his team will obviously
make sure that no such thing can happen.
And obviously the feasibility and the
risk assessment also has to be done
before a visit is arranged and so on. So
all that obviously will be done by the
professionals and hopefully things just
you know everything goes smoothly
wherever whenever Mr. Modi visits some
other country. My point is he will
probably not visit the US anytime soon.
Maybe not as long as Mr. Trump is is
president and he won't even visit some
other country where there is the high
possibility of of having to meet Mr.
Trump. I think Mr. Modi should just
avoid such engagements. And I think
makes sense, right? Makes sense.
Sum Brahmanic says the US is now very
clearly showing the world how powerful
and capable they are and they can
essentially do anything anywhere in the
world. Well,
yeah, now we can see it. I've been
saying it for four years, 5 years. Okay.
So, how can Russia and China counter the
US who is now actually behaving like a
superpower and isolating both the
countries? Please explain in detail.
The US is a superpower. It has always
behaved like a superpower. But in the
past, it did did this in certain ways
that were not very obvious. And that's
why the the world thought that America
is this great champion of human rights
and democracy and freedom and whatnot.
Now we can see what the US is. It's it's
an empire. It's an imperial power,
superpower, whatever you want to call
it. And it's behaving as such openly,
right? So um the US is obviously
doing whatever it wants because it has
global power projection capabilities.
The kind of capabilities that Russia and
China both lack. China has next to no
power projection capabilities.
China has almost no extr territorial
military bases. The same essentially
applies to Russia, right? It it may have
some military bases beyond Russian
territory but those are terrestrial
bases not naval bases and air force
bases terrestrial bases maybe air force
but terrestrial but no naval bases. So
the US has essentially global power
production capability which means it can
do whatever it wants. It can take
Venezuela if it wants it can tomorrow
maybe make a move on Iran if it wants
and the US has this very clear goal
right now to secure as much of the
world's energy supply as possible.
Venezuela, 20% of the world's proven oil
reserves. The US now takes it. Next,
maybe Iran, right? Iran also has a
massive massive uh [clears throat] share
of the world's oil reserves. If the US
takes that, well, that's a major
problem. So, the more of these oil and
energy reserves the Americans start
controlling, the more of a problem it
becomes for especially China. Not so
much for Russia because Russia has its
own energy reserves. Russia doesn't
deserve doesn't depend on any any other
country for energy. Russia is a net
exporter of energy. So Russia will not
be constrained by this. China for China
it's a major major problem right? If the
US starts controlling all these sources
of energy that China depends on.
So by doing all of this the the
Americans are pre putting more and more
pressure on especially China and even
Russia you know. So, [clears throat] so
what can Russia and China do to counter
the US? Well, at this point in time,
there's not much. U Russia and China,
for example, if it comes to Iran,
Russia and China can bolster Iran's
defenses by sending,
you know, military equipment that the
Iranians can use to defend themselves
and prevent a regime change operation or
any kind of anarchy or chaos in the
country. when he hears that Chinese
transport aircraft are arriving in Iran,
right? Maybe they are dispatching
arms, ammunition, whatever the the
government needs. So, what the Russians
and Chinese can do is they can bolster
Iran's uh self-defense capabilities and
military capabilities. Maybe the ch the
Russians can perhaps share some
missiles. Maybe the Iranians don't need
missiles. Maybe the Iranians have
excellent missiles of their own. So
whatever Iran needs, the Russians and
Chinese can perhaps supply Iran with
that. Maybe that helps Iran stay afloat.
But let's say okay, so that's one angle.
What else can Russia and China do? Well,
they will have to become more dependent
on each other. China will have to become
more dependent on Russia for energy
and Russia will may have to become more
dependent on China for other things. And
it makes sense for both Russia and China
to have markets and have other nations
that they can cooperate with which is
where obviously India comes into the
picture because India is not a western
puppet. It's not a western vasal. India
is sovereign but China has
you know created a bunch of self goals
by by by being so hostile towards India
the past several decades. So then the
question is does China Russia and India
have an excellent relationship? The
Americans don't like it. That's why
they're pressuring India to walk away
from Russia but that's not happening. So
what Russia and China can do is they can
augment and and improve their
relationship with India and various
other nations that seek to remain
sovereign. Well, how many of these do we
have? Not too many, right? Do we? Yeah.
So Russia and China become more
interdependent and maybe they maybe
especially China improves its
relationship with India and they both
work on self-defense. Russia what it can
do is is is maybe it can perhaps keep
the war in Ukraine going on so that it
keeps depleting the European nations who
are supporting the Ukrainian war effort.
Um or maybe if Russia calculates its
time then maybe they can quickly end the
war in Ukraine. maybe by taking Kiev or
whatever whatever way they they seek to
end the war in Ukraine.
So yeah, so Ukraine is a factor in this
and China obviously will have to keep on
increasing its military uh capabilities
and so on. So these are the things these
two nations can do. Obviously they are
getting becoming more constrained by the
American actions. Yeah. As as a
consequence of the changes the Americans
are making in the world order. Venezuela
gone. Iran pressure. Who knows what
could happen to Iran. Syria gone, right?
Syria was also a Russian and Chinese
ally or at least partner. That's gone.
So the pieces on the chessboard are
being moved around
and that puts China and Russia both
under increasing pressure. So they're
going to have to work together. They're
going to have to find other nations that
potentially they can work with. And
they're going to have to play defense.
No, they can't play offense. Maybe
Russia can to some extent in Europe, in
Ukraine. China is playing defense. You
will see China is is extremely wary of
any kind of military confrontation.
They will use military force as a
bullying tactic against the weaker
nations like perhaps Taiwan, you know,
but they are mortally afraid, the
Chinese, of any kind of military
entanglement with the US. They don't
want that. The Americans have understood
this very clearly. So they're going to
apply maximum pressure on China through
other means.
Yeah. So that's where we are.
Briangas says why was Zalinski unusually
bitter in his speech towards EU after
all the support he got? Zalinski when
has he not been critical and bitter of
everybody? The first time he visited
Washington DC he had a shouting match
with Trump. Zalinski is alive because of
Trump because of the support that that
the you know Trump led US western
coalition has given to Ukraine but
Zalinsky goes and shouts and fights with
Mr. Trump the guy
I mean he's always been like this right
so uh Zalinsky obviously expects more he
wants more more
he's not satisfied with what what he has
what he wants is he wants to defeat
Russia he wants to go and sit in Moscow
in the Kremlin and take over Russia
that's what maybe what he desires right
uh [clears throat]
so what he wants is he wants to defeat
Russia he wants to take back whatever
territories he has lost including Crimea
And if that happens then maybe he will
be reasonably satisfied and then he will
say let's go now go go go after Moscow.
His demands his his his demands will
never be satisfied. That's the kind of
guy Zilinski is. So yeah that's why he
was bitter. He's always bitter.
Math
in CLA says uh could you please explain
what's currently happening to the Kurds
in Syria? What's India's position in the
matter? Okay. Kurds in Syria. Let's go
to the map.
Um, what's happening to the Kurs is
what's always been happening to them the
past 1,00 or so years, at least the past
couple of centuries. So, Kystan, where
is Kyustan?
It's essentially kind of this region.
Okay. um
eastern Turkey,
north,
western,
Persia, Iran, parts, you know, northern
parts of of Iraq, even some parts,
eastern parts of Syria. This entire
region is what should have been
Kuristan, a nation for the Kurds. But it
was the European nations, European
powers, western powers that you know
designed the maps, the boundaries
between nations in West Asia in the
aftermath of the first and second world
wars and they said that there is no need
for a Kurdistan
and that's why you not have a Kuristan.
So the Kur the Kurdish people they are
oppressed in Turkey, they are oppressed
in Iraq. uh they are also there some of
them also live in in
northwestern Iran and they don't have a
land of or a nation of their own
landless people you know always
oppressed everywhere even the Iranians
don't want a kurasan because it would
then you know take away some Iranian
territory so nobody wants kuristan
everybody wants a kuresh territories
they've taken and the Turks especially
have been extremely um well you could
say brutal towards the Kurds
uh so what's happening now to the Kurds
in Syria
Not just Syria, Iraq, etc. everywhere.
So there is definitely a Kurdish
population in Syria because part of
Kuristan it's currently in Syria. So
what's happening? See what the Americans
want is a regime change into Iran. They
want a regime change in Iran. Now a
direct military operation is maybe not
the best thing because it may not work
in Iran is too large of a nation to be
invaded by a military force. Maybe okay
and and if this happens maybe the maybe
the people will support the the regime
of the laws in the so then what can you
do you can perhaps destabilize Iran
okay by sending in ISIS and whatnot ISIS
al-Qaeda etc terrorists to to create
insurgences and whatnot in Iran so what
you can do so so Turkey allegedly has a
lot of uh connections apparently
allegedly with ISIS and al-Qaeda and uh
Many of these terrorists have been
fighting in Syria. I mean, right now,
Syria is ruled by ISIS, isn't it? Golani
is is an ISIS terrorist and he's now the
president of Syria in Damascus. So,
Syria is ruled by ISIS. In the past, you
had ISIS in Iraq, right? ISIS suddenly
emerged in the 2010s from nowhere. Maybe
it was a rebranded al-Qaeda or whatever.
That's a different story. So, Turkey has
a lot of influence somehow over the ISIS
and al-Qaeda terrorists. So
Turkey seems to have decided that maybe
with maybe with a go ahead from a more
powerful nation perhaps potentially that
we're going to send ISIS and al-Qaeda
terrorists into Iran to fight Iran. But
first we have to make sure that Syria is
completely secure and under under our
control which means that the Kurds
cannot be a resistance force in Syria
anymore. Which means that we have to
neutralize the Kurds. Maybe Syria should
have no Kurdish people.
Maybe that. So that's why there is now
an ISIS al-Qaeda mostly ISIS offensive
against the Kurdish people in Syria. And
maybe it will go into Iran, Iraq also
and eventually maybe into Iran. So
Turkey sees the Kuresh people as its
enemies. The Turks see everybody as
their enemies. Maybe they they don't
want any Kuresh people to exist just
like they don't want any Armenians to
exist.
Right? Uh the Kuresh people by the way
are neither Arabic nor Turk. The Kuresh
people are Indo-Iranian. They're
classified as an Iranian people. They
speak an Iranian language according to
linguistics linguistic classification.
Okay. Um and they practice festivals
like Navros and so on which used to be a
Zorashan festival originally. So that's
the Kurdish people and the Turks they
don't want the Kurds to exist. So nasty
stuff is happening to the Kurds. The
Kurds are fighting and resisting but one
hopes they succeed but yeah
Rushab says how do you see the future of
Iran? The Basie and the IRGC are there
to stay. The protests have no
leadership. So will we see a deal
between the US and Iran? Will Kabi
become moderate and do some deal or will
he be deposed and the regime will adapt
like what happened in Venezuela? Can
they try and use Azeri's kur and Sunnis
or it creates Afghanistan or is the US
doing a deceptive operation where they
might suddenly do something like
Venezuela? What future lies ahead for
Iran and the Houthis? Houthis. Okay.
Houthis.
Okay. So once again map
Houthis are the Ansarah faction in Yemen
and they are allies of Iran. Uh Iran
also has allies in Lebanon Hezbollah and
they used to have an ally in Syria which
no longer exists because now Syria is
ruled by al-Qaeda or sorry ISIS whatever
terrorist Jolani al-Shara or whatever
his name is. So that's that's the deal.
Now coming back to what's happening what
could happen for to Iran. Look, Iran is
too large of a nation to be invaded and
successfully taken. It'll it's it's
possible for sure, but it [snorts] will
lead to complete chaos.
And is it worth spending so much time,
energy, effort, money, especially
billions of dollars, maybe trillions of
dollars into an invasion of Iraq, which
and you see Iran will not go down
without a fight. They know the
government of Iran knows that the
Americans are after oil. If the
Americans try to take Iran, maybe the
Iranians will do exactly what Saddam
Hussein did when the Americans invaded
Iraq, burned the oil wells. That's a
possibility. Uh that would be an
environmental catastrophe and it would
take a lot of time for the Americans to
be able to salvage that and bring that
under control. And obviously Iran has
very very powerful missile capabilities.
They could target all the American bas
bases in the region successfully
potentially. They could even target
Israel, right? So instead of launching
an invasion,
another alternative that the Americans
have is to launch an insurgency through
ISIS terrorists and al-Qaeda terrorists
and all that. And if you look at the
population of Iran, maybe roughly 50%
60% perhaps could be Persians. The rest
are various other ethnic groups like the
Azeris, Azarbaijanis,
um Arabs,
Kurish people also but those are more
Iranian than Arab or whatever. So you
have various you have the Balois also
right in the southeast of Iran.
Um so
the Americans could try and launch
insurgencies in Iran.
Um they could use Pakistan. Pakistan is
a tried and tested terrorist nation.
Pakistan is the is is the is the
greatest terrorist nation of the world.
The global epicenter of terrorism. I
mean Pakistan is the world's university
of terrorism. They you don't need to
teach them anything. So the Pakistanis
could create trouble for Iran. Al-Qaeda
ISIS could create trouble from Iran from
the west. Right. So maybe that could be
done. Uh like you saw the protests have
no leadership. uh possibly no
leadership, right? So what could happen?
Maybe that happens. I think an invasion
of Iran, military invasion is slightly
less likely than launching a
destabilizing set of operations on Iran,
insurgencies, terrorism, all that. That
obviously I think could probably be more
likely. So what could happen? Will we
see a deal between the US and Iran?
Well, if
that happens, does the Iranian
government have any legitimacy anymore?
If they agree to a deal which which
obviously makes Iran a vasal state of
the US. If there's a deal between US and
Iran, it obviously will involve energy.
The Americans will insist that we
control the energy. You sell your oil to
us only or to nations that we approve,
which means no more China or whatever.
Then will Iran agree to that? Will
Russia agree to that? Of course, Russia,
if Iran agrees, Russia can't do a thing.
China can't do a thing. But uh
essentially for Iran, from their
perspective and from their own language
and their past pronouncements, it means
doing a deal with the devil. Because the
Iranian government calls the United
States Shaitan Borg, the great Satan. So
will they do a deal with a nation they
call the great Satan? A deal with the
devil. I doubt it very much.
So there is no deal. Kane will not
become moderate or whatever and do some
deal. Very unlikely. Can the Americans
do what they did in Venezuela? Maybe pay
off a bunch of lower ranking Iranian
officials and get rid of the top guy and
have a puppet come in place. They may
try that. But will it work? I think it's
uh less likely.
It's not impossible.
That I think could be the best solution
for the Americans. Um don't do a
military invasion. Launch insurgencies
and terrorist operations across Iran
using ISIS, using Pakistani terrorists
and so on.
And by that put pressure on the Iranian
regime and then pay off a bunch of
Iranian high-ranking people, the key
people in the government to expel or
take out the top leadership and then
install a puppet of the US. That I think
is the best option for the US. It will
um cost them the least and it will you
know yeah cost them the least. no
trillions of dollars to spend on a
military operation.
Um, and that by doing that you can
actually take over the entire nation
essentially intact. All the all the
assets all the all the all the resources
of the nation intact.
So that could be the best way forward
for the US,
right? Uh so what future lies ahead for
Iran? Um more and more pressure on on
Iran. Maybe the Turks etc. will
launch some kind of ISIS operation
that sort of thing. Maybe the Pakistanis
will be involved in terrorist activities
in Iran. Maybe Iran comes under more and
more pressure and then the Americans
maybe try to buy some Iranians off and
effective regime change at the very top
while keeping the rest of the government
structure intact. So it looks like the
there was a coup within Iran and the
government of Iran has decided to have a
new leader now and miraculously this new
leader now is pro- US. That's also a
possibility. I think that is the ideal
way forward forward for the US
[clears throat]
makes the most sense and costs the
least.
So will that succeed?
[clears throat]
depends on to what extent the Pakistani
potential terrorists and potential
Turkey ISIS terrorists can destabilize
Iran and the extent to which the
Americans can and Israelis and whoever
else can forment more protests and so on
in Iran. If that continues and there is
more pressure on the government and then
there is more of an incentive for some
people in the Iranian government to to
accept a US proposal for regime change
which leaves the rest of the structure
intact.
So [clears throat] I think that could be
the the angle the Americans will work
on. Let's see how it goes.
Mclivven says, [clears throat] "So Iran
temporarily turned on Starlink to track
down and arrest the users. Maybe it
wasn't such a bad idea to let it operate
in India." Okay. Okay. What Iran did is
this. They turned off the internet in
Iran.
and they had the means to prevent
Starlink from operating in Iran by GPS
spoofing and some other um means but
they turned that off too for a while. So
Iran first switched off internet. The
government of Iran first it the first
thing it did was switch off internet in
Iran. Turn off internet. No internet
access. Then they allowed Starlink beams
to operate in Iran uninterrupted. They
had the means to jam the Starlink
signals
but they for some time stopped jamming
the Starling signals. So the Starling
signals then then were able to come
properly and then whoever had Starling
receiver devices in Iran. They started
using that
and the Iranian government had a way of
finding out where is Starlink being used
in Iran. pinpoint the location so that
they could go and arrest those people
because see Starlink is not legal in
Iran.
Starlink equipment is not legal in Iran.
If some individuals have Starlink
receivers in Iran, it means they are
assets of foreign powers.
Right?
So Iran did this to identify and
pinpoint the people who were foreign
agents in Iran and then they went ahead
and arrested them. Once this was done,
they once again jammed the Starlink
signals
and then maybe they put on the internet
again for after a while. I don't know if
they did but yeah. So that's what was
done.
Okay. Now is it a good idea to let
Sarling operate in India? I don't think
it's a good idea. I don't think so
because see if we allow Starlink to
operate in India then anybody can buy
Starlink receivers and whatnot and then
if India let's say in the future so it
means that everybody it means that a
large number of people have Starlink
receivers maybe hundreds of thousands of
people and then let's say if for for
whatever reason India has to bring
internet down for let's say 24 hours in
some city for some reason or maybe some
state then you may still have a a few 10
thousand tens of thousands of people who
have Starling devices there then how do
you identify the ones who are foreign
agents you can't
right you can't so I don't think it's a
good idea to allow Starlink to operate
in India why do we need that
if we need space or satellite internet
why can't we have our own service why do
we need a foreign service I don't think
it's a good idea at all
Heisenberg says Is China's presence in
the Indian Ocean reversible or or has
India already lost critical strategic
space? See, nothing is irreversible?
What kind of presence does China have in
the Indian Indian Ocean region? Let's
let's take a look at the map. Uh this is
the map of the Indian Ocean region. Uh
obviously it is there are two there's
the west coast of India which is the
so-called Arabian sea which I call the
sea of Sarashtra and you have the east
east coast of India which is the bay of
Bengal or the or the Kolinga bahas saga.
So that is the coastal regions of India.
Then we have the Lakshadep Sea. And then
you have the greater Indian Ocean over
here which goes all the way to the Gulf
of Malaca, the straight of Mala to
Western Australia, all the way to
Antarctica and over here in East Africa.
So this is the Indian Ocean region. Now
what kind of presence does China have?
China operates submarines and some
ships, you know, some some warships in
the region, naval ships. And the Chinese
often participate in antipiriracy
activities, naval activities uh of the
horn of Africa region. This this region,
okay, this is this region is called the
horn of Africa. In this region, you have
Somali pirates and whatnot. And the
Chinese often send warships in the
region under the pretext of engaging in
antipiriracy activities.
And the Chinese sometimes they they send
submarines and warships to dock off the
port of Karachi. Okay. And the Chinese
also have uh they operate
um a port a naval port in Djibouti. Uh
shall we see what kind of um what they
have in Djibouti?
So if you see here
um
what what naval facilities do we have
here? Uh you will see a Chinese terminal
and whatnot. Okay. I can't see
tell which one is the Chinese. There's
an American operation also over here.
So, this seems like a
Okay, so I'll I'll not waste your time
by trying to identify which is which.
But the Chinese operate um they they
have a naval base in Djibouti. Okay, so
that's one thing they have. They may
have access to Karachi port or
definitely uh Guadada port
and uh possibly Haman Tota. I'm not sure
if that's still something they operate
and uh possibly something in Madagascar.
And definitely
um
not sure about definitely not Thailand
or Burma.
maybe something in Bangladesh but
Bangladesh is now a US facile so it
doesn't work so that's the kind of you
know scattered activity they have that
they're trying to construct a string of
pearls did not really work out for them
uh so they have some presence in the
Indian Ocean region now is this
irreversible or is it reversible nothing
is irreversible has India lost critical
strategic spa space not at all we can
transform the Indian Ocean region into
an Indian zone by simply
by simply putting out more warships. All
you need to do is to build a bunch of
warships, not necessarily very expensive
warships
and have them patrol the region, visibly
patrol the region. So wherever you go,
you must not be far from an Indian ship.
You should see visibly that there are
Indian ships all over the place. that
will immediately is very straightforward
in a very straightforward way give India
an overwhelming
advantage over China. So if the Chinese
have a few ships here and there it will
make no difference.
What India needs to do is put out
construct more ships warships in large
numbers including submarines. The
submarines are the are the critical
aspect in this not aircraft carriers.
Some of the easiest things to do is one
of the easiest things to do is to build
build a bunch of missile boats. Boots
that don't stray far away from shore,
maybe a 100 nautical miles or so. And
each missile boat should not cost more
than $20 million to build, which is
peanuts in terms of actual money.
And have each missile boat carry three
brahos missiles. That's frightening
enough. If you build a hundred of those,
that is frightening for any adversary
because you know, you never know from
what direction of missile is going to
come and hit you. So that's one thing.
Then you can build destroyers and and
corvettes and whatnot and a bunch of
submarines. You have that all over the
place. What can China do, right? There's
nothing that's re irreversible.
McLevin says most of the powerful
positions in the world are held by
boomers. Boomers. They are way too old
to work but but still don't want to give
up their seats. Look at Biden and Trump.
Do you think things will be better if
the younger generation comes to power?
Makes no difference. Okay, sure. You
know, if you if you if you have an
elderly leader, elderly person who's
leading your nation, maybe the
leadership is not that dynamic. But look
at Trump. He's an elderly guy. I mean,
look at his leadership. He's rampaging
across the world making America great
again. Isn't he succeeding? So what?
Biden is a different story. Biden wasn't
fully there.
Biden wasn't fully there. Somebody else
was running the country clearly. So and
it wasn't Kamala Harris was somebody
else entirely. Kamala Harris was
definitely fully there but she is not
she wasn't competent to run a country.
So the US is that sort of country that
even if the leadership is incompetent,
the visible leadership is incompetent,
you have people running the country and
it it's it's taken care of. When it
comes to other nations,
so Trump is a great example of maybe
he's a boomer, but he's a tremendous
leader even now at this age. Putin
is also probably a baby boomer. What's a
boomer? First of all, let's try and
understand what boomer is. It comes from
the term baby boomers. That's a
generation, right? Baby boomers.
Generation. Okay. What's baby boomers?
People born from 1946 to 64.
So, I'm sure Mr. Xiinping, Mr. Modi, Mr.
Putin, and Mr. Trump, all of these
leaders are baby boomers, right? Most
likely all of them are.
Mr. Putin is the best leader we can you
can the Russian people can ask for
today. Mr. Mr. Bodhi is the best prime
minister we can ask for today for India.
Probably Mr. Fijian is the best leader
to run in his country. Um so it's not
like age matters as long as the leader
is still all there and competent and
high quality leadership is is what
you're seeing. Uh but will things be
better if younger younger people come to
power?
Could be. Could be. It's always nice to
have a person who's reasonably young
maybe 40s to 60s in politics. 40 is
really young. 50 is also young. 60 is
like, okay, you're getting there now.
So, a person who's between 40 and 60 is
considered young in leadership and
politics. Below the age of 40, I don't
think a person is wise enough to be to
lead a country. Okay?
And you've had people who led countries
at much younger ages. Of course.
Of course. And if you're lucky, that
person does a good job, especially with
the right kind of advisers and all. But
ideally a leader should be above 40.
So I don't think the things will be
better if younger generations come to
power. I don't think the world will be
more peaceful if if younger people come
to power. The the nature of power never
changes and national interest never
changes.
So I don't think it makes much of a
difference actually unless you have a
leader who is elderly and and and
no longer fit for the job. In that case,
your country suffers.
Okay, let's move into history now.
Vashisha says, "Did the Germans invent
blitzkrieg?" So, what's blitzkrieg?
Blitzkrieg is tactics. What tactics? You
concentrate all your
force, all your power in a single point
essentially in a very narrow space and
blast through uh the enemy's defenses.
It's warfare. I'm talking about military
warfare here. So what the Germans did in
the second world war is blitzkrieg
tactics. U you had the French Majino
line which was a series of
fortifications and defenses and the
French forces were concentrated along
the Majino line. The Germans what they
did was they focused all their firepower
all their forces in one point on the
Majino line broke blasted through that
and just made the Mino line irrelevant.
They just went through this and invaded
France and the defenders were left
behind. That's what the Germans did.
Now, is this something new? So basically
tactics are about focusing your
firepower, your your military force in
one place, blasting through it
and that tactical victory you then
translate it into systemic collapse for
the opposition by making their defenses
irrelevant.
So you mobilize your your infantry, your
tanks, your armored divisions, your air
support, everything in one place and
blast through that. That is a
blitzkrieg.
Did the Germans invent it? Not
necessarily invented, but they took it
to the next level. Um the Mongols
probably used blitzkrieg tactics. The
Mongols were really good at that. They
also had this thing you know where they
would the mo the Mongols had highly
mobile
uh warriors, horse based warriors,
cavalry both of them and they had they
employed bows and arrows and very
powerful. They were [clears throat]
really skilled at that and they were
really really fast and they could they
also used similar tactics. But what the
Germans did was they brought in elements
of mechanized warfare that were not
available to the Mongols. So the Mongols
also used eventually catapults and this
massive equipment,
but those were not mobile, right? Those
are very heavy and very hard to move.
They had to be dismantled to move them
from one city to another. But if you
have a tank and that's way more powerful
than a catapult, it can build bring down
buildings and whatnot. So and that's
pretty mobile. Tanks can move really
fast. So the so the the Germans brought
tanks um other mechanized ar artillery,
mechanized columns
and even air power and brought all of
these elements and aspects together
along with infantry infantry and whatnot
in into the into the set of tactics into
the mix in Blitzkrieg and that's that's
something that had not been done before.
So the Germans did not invent blitzkrieg
but they took it to the next level.
And the tactics India used for example
in 1971 those are once again blitzkrieg
tactics
right same tactics but we didn't call it
blitzkrieg but those were the same
tactics the Americans in desert storm
use blitz blitzkrieg tactics so
blitzkrieg works it's about bringing all
your forces concentrating everything in
one place
uh causing
effecting strategic sorry tactical
success there and translating the
tactical success into systemic failure
for the for the enemy. That's blitzkrieg
and yeah.
Okay.
Amisha says slavery in France was
abolished in 1794. Was it 1794? Was it
1789?
Okay. Whatever year 1794 let's say
Napoleon Budapart relegalized slavery in
1802 where emancipated slaves forced
black forced back into slavery. How did
relegalizing work in practice?
So slavery was indeed abolished sometime
in the late 1700s 17
whatever year it was.
I was under the impression it was 1789
or something. Let's just double check
it. I'm just not letting my mind is not
letting that go. Uh when did France
abolish
sla abolish slavery? Slavery
18 not colonies man.
Yeah, Amisha is absolutely right. It was
1794. Okay. During the revolution, it
was reinstated by Napoleon in 1802 and
then 1848. Okay. So that was a deal.
France abolished slavery but Napoleon
Bonapart to the great the great man says
no no no we need more slavery slavery is
manic we want it yes we is so let's have
slavery all over again so Napoleon
relegalizes slavery now what effect did
it have France had a bunch of colonies
Moraicius it had colonies in in Heii
some other colonies Martineik and what
not. Okay, bunch of colonies. The thing
is this
1794 slavery is abolished on paper. But
in many of these colonies, slavery was
still there. [laughter] Maybe the papers
had not reached there or maybe the the
the slave owners were just were just
dragging their feet and you know, let's
keep it going as long as there's no
punishment for us or there's no real
push back. So in many of these places,
slavery was still kind of continuing.
For example, Mauritius, most likely
slavery still existed
in 1802.
So when Napoleon relegalizes slavery in
1802, it made no difference in Mauritius
because slavery was anyway going on.
Even though they had not implemented the
abolition of slavery, slavery in Heii,
you had the great
uh the great uh freedom fighter.
How do how do you write that in English?
Okay. Sounds very different in French.
Okay. This guy. So
he was born a slave in in Heii. It was
called Sumang. It's now called Hei. So
he was born there. And when Napoleon
relegalized slavery,
Tusan Lu fought he fought the French. it
I think it was 1804 two years later that
Heii became independent. They defeated
the French. Uh which year did Heii
become independent? Once again
independence independence year
1804. There you have it. Right. So the
French tried to reimpose slavery in Heii
but they failed and became independent.
Heii won its independence from France in
1804 after a military conflict. They
defeated the French. So they didn't work
in Heii.
Maicius slavery never went away. So it
made no difference. In some places
slavery had been abolished and you had
people who had been emancipated
means freed from slavery. What happened
to those people? The emancipation was
ruled back and they were brought back
into slavery.
Right?
So how did relegalizing work in
practice? Relegalizing means you don't
just send a paper. You send a bunch of
soldiers armed forces with with the
papers to enforce the relegalization.
So it was done through force. If you
just tell the bunch bunch of former
slaves who had been freed that you are
slaves again, they will resist that.
Right? So you have to arrive with
reinforcements.
So the French sent troops to various
colonies
to re to reimpose slavery and in many
places where people had been emancipated
freed they were dragged back into
slavery and those who resisted were
punished in various ways including the
harshest ways. U so that's how relegal
relegalizing worked in practice. You
don't you don't merely send papers that
it's slavery is legal again. you send
reinforcements to enforce the
relleization of slavery. So sometimes
you make people slaves all over again.
Sometimes you what you do is you give
them some kind of contract indenture
contract which essentially translates
into slavery all over again like what
was done to Indians by the British.
Um yeah so that that's how it was done.
It was done by force because nobody will
willingly become a slave again. So you
had to send troops and and
reinforcements to enforce this. That's
how the French did this. Pretty nasty
stuff.
Swami says, "What's the history of Jean
Dak, Joan of Ark? Why did England
execute her?" So her actual name was
Jean D.
Jean Dak. Okay. In English, she's called
Jun of Ark, but the actual French name
is Jean Dak. So as you can see she was
born sometime in 1412 or something and
uh she was murdered in 1431.
We're talking about the 15th century
here. Okay. So what's the story of this
girl? So this period is the 100 day 100
year war between England and France.
It's a period of time when England
claims French France as its own
territory.
There are see these two nations they
have a thousand-y year enmity France and
England. There have been times when
France has claimed England and you have
French kings or French speaking kings
ruling over England and then you have
this 100 year war period when the
English claimed France and they wanted
to capture French territory and make
France an English colony or or or an
English possession or English territory
and that the war is going on. So you
have this king called Charles the 6 7th
Charles I the 7th right Charles IIth
Charles IIth u who was the French leader
and uh
we're talking about the early 15th
century Joan Jean this girl is born
somewhere in the northwest of France
okay um 1412 or thereabouts
and when she's a teenager she has
visions
she has visions of I don't know visions
of some kind and uh visions from angels
or saints or something and she and these
visions tell her that she she she has to
go and fight for France. She has to go
and fight for the king of France or or
the uncrowned king of France. The dufa
the dufa is the uncrowned king of France
Charles II. He had not been crowned yet.
So the visions told her that you have to
go and fight for France. Fight for
France's freedom against the English. Go
support your king. make him king. He's
not king yet. And so on. So she somehow
goes to the court of the Dufur of
France, Charles II, and she's able to
convince Charles the 7th that, you know,
she has been sent by God.
She has divine blessings or whatever.
And uh she is sent to fight a battle.
Uh it was Orlon, was it Orlian?
I think it was Orlans. So she goes with
the French troops to this city that the
English are besieging Orleans and she's
able to inspire the troops into
defeating the English and then she's
sent somewhere else and she succeeds
there also right so she becomes this
sensation this this divine girl girl
with divine divine blessing a teenager
16 17 or whatever years old right and
she's wearing armor she's wearing
soldiers dress costume with armor and
she's fighting She got she got wounded
in all but she was able to succeed
and she really galvanizes the troops and
boosts their morale and the the French
are resurgent and because of the success
um Charles II is then crowned the king
of France right so it looks like because
of Jean Joan of Ark God is on the side
of the French he is blessed by the god
by by god not the gods They don't have
the gods. They only have one god. And
God is now on the side of France.
Eventually, um, in some battle, she's
captured by the English. Maybe there's
some treason. Maybe she was captured by
somebody and handed over to the British,
whatever. Um, then the British they they
what they do is they try her for for
heresy or something. So, it was like
this. See this girl, this young girl,
peasant girl who has no military
training.
She has been able to inspire the French
armies into victory over England.
That clearly indicates that she has
divine blessing. Now, how do you deal
with that?
One way of dealing with that is to claim
that it was not divine blessing. It was
satanic blessing. it was the devils or
whatever who had who who were possessed
this girl
because if you say she's a she's a
divinely blessed girl or something then
it means that God was actually fighting
on the side of France. So how do you how
do you
how do you challenge that? You the only
way to challenge it is by claiming that
she was actually possessed by devil
devil or Satan or something like that or
demons demons. Your visions were demonic
visions. Satanic visions and you
actually are are possessed and you and
this girl this girl is wearing male
dress. She's wearing male clothing and
and armor. That is obviously completely
contrary to the natural order of things
and the will of God. That is so
uncchristian for a woman to wear male
costume and fight as a male soldier.
Right? So they prepared these charges
against this girl and then they said
that they told the girl they brought her
to court and there was this you know
Christian hearing and all and she was
said that she'll be immediately executed
unless she recantss or whatever. So or
or or she gives an undertaking that she
will no longer do these things and you
know my visions may be perhaps were not
divine. So she agreed to write write
this or or or put her signature or
whatever it was on this confession and
she agreed that uh I will not wear male
male clothing and that and therefore
therefore I will not offend God anymore.
But then she's found to be wearing male
clothing again in the prison because
apparently the only clothing that was
given to her was male clothing.
So they did not give her female
clothing. They gave her male clothing to
wear and that's the only thing she had
to wear because it was cold and you wear
something right. So whatever available
you wear it. So she's again found to be
wearing male clothing. So they first
tried to they they first gave her gave
her the opportunity to to change her
ways so that the entire persecution can
look merciful.
But then they gave her male clothing to
wear. So they trapped her by doing so.
And eventually they said that you know
what she is not really a divinely
blessed girl. She is she was the visions
she had were demonic visions and we gave
her the chance to to mend her ways but
she in kept she insisted on keeping on
wearing male clothing and so on which is
why she has to be
um she is condemned to death and she was
then executed by the English. They
burned her alive at the age of 18 or 19.
Poor girl,
right? All she did was fight for her
country.
Um, so that's the deal about Joan of
Ark. The British were very nasty, very
cruel, but
you know,
they did what they had to do, I suppose,
from their perspective, the English.
Uh, so that's why England executed Jon
of Arc. Eventually, I think it was in
the 20th century that the the Catholic
Church u
uh sainted her or something, beautified
her. They declared her a saint and she's
one of the saints u patron saints or
whatever in France. So, if you go to
Leon today, I'm sure you will find a
statue of Jon of Arc there and so on.
That's the story of Joan of Ark. Jean
Amisha says, "Were the Irish and
Italians really considered
non-white in America. Were the Irish and
Italians really considered non-white in
America?
What race were they? Uh why not white?
And when and how did they become white?
So look, the Irish and Italians
obviously are European people, right? No
question about that. So see in the US
there's there's
we have to look at it from two
perspectives. There is something called
legal race. Okay, the Americans had
something called legal race. Uh so in
American law, white meant European. No
matter what part of Europe you came
from, you were legally white if you were
a European. And Irish and Italians
obviously counted as white because they
from from the from the very start in
American law because they were from
Europe. So legally
they were white. They were eligible for
naturalization. Okay? And they were
never barred as a race the way Asians or
Africans were. Not Africans, Africans
were slaves. But Asians were barred from
immigrating into the US and becoming
naturalized citizens. Italians and Irish
were not barred like that. So legally
they were white. But there is something
called social status or social race,
racialized status. So in everyday life,
so despite being legally white, in
everyday life, the Italian and Irish
people were portrayed as a different or
inferior kind of white person. They were
often compared to Africans and non-white
races and they were described as being
somehow lesser
than proper white people, biologically
lesser, morally lesser, culturally
lesser than the Nordic people. Okay, so
they were racially stigmatized. They
were treated as if they were white but
not quite white. Okay, that sort of
thing. They were not legally non-white
in the way that black people or Asian
people were. So why is this so? So in
the 19th century racial thinking in the
western world,
Europe was split into multiple races.
See from an Indian or non European
perspective, we see the white people as
one people, right? White people,
you don't see Russians as non-white, do
you? You don't see the French and the
Germans being two different kinds of
white. You see them all as white people.
But in their perspective, okay, Europe
was divided into various races. You had
the Anglo-Saxons, you had the Nordic
people, Nordic people, Anglo-Saxons,
Celtic people, Slavic people, the
Mediterranean races and so on. And each
of these was ranked differently in a
hierarchy.
Okay? So the Irish, so one of the things
about the Irish people, there are two,
this is an oversimplification, but if
you visit Ireland, there are two kinds
of Irish people. There's the red head
redhaired red-headed Irish and there's
the black Irish. What's black Irish?
That's You have some Irish people who
have got jet black hair, right? So
you've got Irish with fair hair and
you've got Irish with black hair. So
there's two kinds of Irish even in
Ireland and that's a whole different
story. So the Irish
are were not considered to be
Anglo-Saxons or Nordic. They were
considered to be Celtic people and they
obviously are Celtic people and the
stereotype was that Celtic people are
less intelligent. They are more
hottempered in tempmperate and the
Celtic people are naturally suited for
survile labor
and they are naturally diff differential
to their superiors to their betters who
were the Anglo-Saxons and the and the
the Nordics. Okay. Um anyway, all these
these these terrible cartoons and carry
catchers that depicted Irish people with
with uh you know comparing them with
monkeys essentially that sort of thing
comparing them with black people also um
and so on that sort of thing. And the
Italians they were obviously not Celtic
but they are part of the what what was
considered to be the Mediterranean race
which is a darker race. Okay. And it was
believed that they are closer to the
Asian people or to Africans but not they
are very very different from the Nordic
and Anglo-Saxon people. They're not
really white. I mean if you go to Greece
today for example, okay, Italy, Greece,
neighboring regions. You go to Greece
today, maybe four to 5% of Greek people
have blonde hair and that to not the
Nordic blonde but the dishwater blonde,
dark blonde. Maybe four to 5% of Greek
people have blonde hair. The
overwhelming majority of Greek Greek
people have dark hair. When it comes to
blue eyes, maybe 5 to 10% of of Greek
people have blue eyes or green eyes or
gray eyes. The rest of Greek people,
more than 10% have brown eyes. And the
Greek skin color, well, it's closer to
Persia and West India, Western India,
then to Europe, then to the, you know,
the the white European ideal, Nordic or
Anglo-Saxon ideal. So clearly the the
Italians and the Greeks are more brown
than white.
So there was that also. Uh then there's
religion. Okay, religion is an is is an
issue because uh the Irish and the
Italians were Catholic but uh the
country the United States was a strongly
Protestant country. You know the roots
from the Mayflower and whatnot were
strongly Protestant roots. um and prot
the Catholics well well you know there
was this anti-atholic Catholic sentiment
so Catholics were considered to be more
superstitious than the Protestants um
less industrious than the Protestants
more violent than the Protestants and so
on and once again the Irish and the
Italians their languages obviously
native languages were different their
accents in English were different and so
on their customs were also foreign and
so
Um so there are these issues and then
you have you know the Irish and the
Italians were poor people. They were new
immigrants and they competed for the for
the poor jobs you know the working man's
job and all that and that led to
friction and competition and so on which
is an issue. Um and they were typically
engaged in work that black laborers
would do that sort of thing. They would
work in fields. They would work in
dockyards. They would work in small
businesses typically in places where
black people work would work. So they
were associated with black people. That
sort of thing. So because of this you
had this issue that the Irish and the
Italians were regarded as the perhaps in
the Americas the lowest class of white
people. Uh eventually what happened in
the late 19th century 20th century Irish
men started gaining power in politics,
urban politics. They started becoming
parts of police forces. They became
parts of labor unions especially in
cities like New York, Boston,
Philadelphia. Okay. They became insiders
in white urban power structures.
Italians moved from the lowskilled
trades into highly skilled trades,
shopkeeping, uh various
businesses and occupations and so on. So
overall they started rising in social
status and and so on and they obviously
consciously
decided to distance themselves from the
black people. Maybe they became even
more racist towards black people than
the other whites were. And that's how
eventually things changed. So that's how
they became white so to say. And
eventually what happens is that people
assimilate people you know there are
intermarages between Anglo-Saxons and
white and Irish people Anglo-Saxons and
Italian people and eventually the race
distinctions uh eventually
dissolve. So eventually that's what
happened. So that's how the Irish and
the Italians were considered kind of
non-white
and they faced a lot of discrimination,
persecution, oppression, whatever. But
eventually they were able to overcome
these
these these hardships.
Okay.
Okay. This is a question that has come
from Twitter by K9 XE Empire. Uh let me
come here and this is the question here.
So I asked Gemini for its pure
conclusion about the Arian invasion
theory versus 10 kings war theory which
I got to know from my channel and it
provided me with this answer. What's my
opinion on this? So Gemini's final
verdict is is this. Gemini says, "If I
have to draw a conclusion based purely
on logic and available data, first of
all, the Arian invasion theory is a
myth. It makes no sense militarily or
archaeologically. Second, the 10 kings
theory is culturally superior. It it
fits the texts. It fits the rear river
geology, the Saraspati and all that and
the psychology of the Indian people who
have no memory of arriving from outside.
It solves the paradox of prosperity that
you mentioned earlier. However, the
migration theory is scientifically
dominant. Until out of India theory
proponents can explain why the step DNA
appears in India only after 2000 BC, the
migration theory remains the standard
scientific model. My unbiased
conclusion, Gemini says, "The truth is
likely somewhere in the middle, a
nuanced reality where Indian
civilization was indigenous as the 10
kings theory says, but interacted
significantly with Central Asian groups
who migrated in and mixed over thousands
of years as the genetics say. So what is
my view on what Gemini has to say?
Look,
Gemini makes sense here.
The 10 k what is this 10 kings theory?
First of all let's understand the the 10
kings theory is all it obviously refers
to the battle of the 10 kings that is
mentioned in the rigida and the rigida
is a very ancient text. It's not
something that was written in 1500 BC
which is arbitrarily assigned to it. It
was clearly written a long time before
1500 BC when the Sarasbati was still in
her prime 1500 BC the Sarasati had dried
out in the southern half of our course.
So clearly the rigid was written closer
to the time the Sarasati was in her
prime that is like the last time it was
in her prime. The river was about 6,000
BC. The closer to that time maybe 4,000
BC maybe even 3,000 BC but definitely
not 2,000 BC or even 3,000 BC doesn't
make sense. Maybe 4,000 5,000 6,000 BC
BC is the Rigida's probable time period.
Okay. Um and in the Rigida we have the
we have this the oldest geopolitical
event in the world warfare. Yeah. the
battle of the 10 kings. Um, and that
kind of explains the dispersal of the
Indo-Uropean languages outside of India
and the formation of the Indian
psyche, the Indian ethos and so on. So
that's the 10 kings theory, right? That
that is the essential origin of Indian
civilization that after the battle of
the 10 kings it was decided that
when a yagna is done we will not merely
allow we we will not merely welcome the
the vic gods but all the other gods of
all the other Indian people who may not
be vicin that's why we have so many gods
today in Hinduism you're all welcome all
your gods are welcome we are all now
going to be one people
so that's kind of the origins of Indian
civilization, right? One of the the
origins of of the idea of India, let's
say that is the original idea of India,
right? Indian civilization obviously
goes back much before that also. So that
is the 10 kings theory. So Gemini says
the truth is somewhere in the middle
most likely a nuance reality where
Indian civilization was indigenous and I
completely agree with this. What is what
are the two
main characteristics of Indian
civilization?
First, there are two things that are
central to Indian civilization. First is
what we call Hinduism
which includes all these different
you know philosophical parts or
philosophical schools of thought you
know vidanta naya vashik vashik uh yoga
mimmansa charvaka bodha jaya all of that
all of this is part of what we call
Hinduism very ancient the oldest known
religion right so the first component of
Indian civilization is what we call
Hinduism. The second component is the
linguistic core which is Sanskrit.
So Gemini says that Indian civilization
which means Hinduism and Sanskrit was
indigenous to India. Well, I completely
agree with Gemini on this. And then our
people interacted significantly with
Central Asian groups who migrated in and
mixed over thousands of years. I
completely agree with that too.
I completely agree with that. See the
core claim of the Arian invasion or
migration theory.
Okay. The hidden claim
the core hidden claim of the Arian
invasion or migration theory is that
Hinduism and Sanskrit are foreign to
India. They were brought in by invaders
or migrants. And Gemini says that is
completely wrong. Gemini disagrees with
that. And I completely agree with
Gemini. Gemini of course we had
interactions with Central Asian groups.
They did migrate into India over
thousands of years. Right? After
thousands of years after the Rigida was
written,
Gemini is completely right. I completely
agree with this. So this migration
theory is scientifically dominant which
Gemini says here migration theory is
scientifically dominant. It's that
central Asian groups from time to time
over thousands of years migrated into
India and brought in Central Asian
genetics. Of course,
today every single ethnic group in the
world wants to migrate to the United
States because it is so prosperous, best
quality of life and in the past you had
India that was that in that situation.
So everybody wanted to migrate to India.
So you would obviously have genetic
influx into India from time to time all
the time over thousands of years and
that's why we have central Asian
genetics in India. You know people in
various parts of India will have some
percentage of Central Asian genetics.
What's the big deal? Of course it's
there.
But to claim that Hinduism and Sanskrit
came from outside of India, that is
completely incorrect. And Gemini
recognizes that. You see, Gemini
recognizes that Indian civilization was
indigenous, which means Hinduism and
Sanskrit were indigenous. Didn't come
from outside. Completely agree with
this.
So yeah, [clears throat]
Gemini, good to see a large language
model that actually is makes sense. It's
[snorts] it's it's supposed to make
sense and it is making sense over here.
Absolutely. So I agree with this. All
right.
Gaj Nulk says, "Was worship through fire
such as in Jagnas the primary the
original primary method of worship done
by prehistoric humans? Given that
prehistoric humans would virtually
always have a campfire burning in or
near their places of residence, homes,
but construction of large idols would
require more effort and construction of
artistically sculpted metal idols took
off on a large scale only recently in
human history. So was worship through
fire the original primary method of
worship done by prehistoric humans?
Well, actually no.
fire worship. We don't find evidence of
fire worship in ancient human
archaeological evidence, evidence from
of ancient humans. So what is the
evidence of religion that we find when
it comes to ancient humans?
We find burial goods. So when a human
being a deceased dead person has been
buried you find that that body has been
buried with various goods.
If it's a warrior it will be a sword,
maybe it will be some shells. Maybe it
will be some valuable items. So items
that are valuable in the real world but
you are burying with that person.
Why bury it with a dead person when you
can actually use it and it's valuable to
you but you still bury it with the
person which means that you are taking
something that's precious valuable and
you are burying it forever
which means that you assign a tremendous
amount of value to that person who has
been buried. Maybe you love that person.
Maybe it's broken your heart that person
died and maybe you want that person to
enjoy whatever you're burying with with
him or her in their afterlife which is
obviously a religious concept right
religious or spiritual concept. So you
find human burials with grave goods that
date back hundreds not hundreds of
thousands of years maybe maybe up to 100
thousand years. Then you have pigments
ochre red ochre that that you know you
find on people's faces on skulls and all
which obviously once again why would you
when you bury somebody put red ochre
pigment on their faces and bodies. Maybe
clearly it will have some kind of
religious or spiritual significance.
Maybe red red ochre was auspicious or
something maybe it will help them help
ease their path in the afterlife or
whatever then you will find even near
burials if you study the soil around the
around the skeleton that's buried you'll
find pollen pollen comes from flowers so
people buried with flowers I mean it's
such a touching and and emotional thing
right you you bury a person with flowers
so you find all these things
and then you find um cave art, cave
painting and all with figures that with
with symbolism that that could signify
religious uh
religion of some kind.
What else you find these little what
they call Venus statueets uh female
figures
that again could have some religious or
whatever connotations and whatnot.
So these are the kind of uh
archaeological
um artifacts [snorts]
and evidences that we find of religious
and spiritual
practices and behavior. Cave art, wall
art, rock art, statueets, figurines,
burial goods, burial pigments, flowers
in in burials and so on. This is what we
find in the archaeological record as
evidence of spiritual and religious
practices and beliefs.
Okay, we find campfires and whatn not
but we never find campfires and other
other fire other evidence of fire which
seems to have any religious
significance.
We we find it you know as something that
was used for cooking or whatever or for
warmth but you never find anything that
indicates any special religious
significance. Um you know typically in
in in Hinduism we have the Vic falcon
falcon-shaped fire altar in which we do
the yagjana yagna right that is a very
specific way of constructing a fire and
you will see all kinds of offerings that
are offered in there you don't find any
of that in ancient
um archaeological evidence
so looks like fire worship was something
specific to the Arian people to the
Indians and the Iranians
doesn't look like it was there anywhere
else in the world. So in Yajjnas what we
have is we have a pantheon of the gods
the Vic gods and who is the messenger of
the Vic gods it's Agni. So if you want
to offer
offerings to the Vic gods you have to
offer it to Agni. Agni is the messenger
the witness of the gods and whatever you
offer to Agni Agni will take it to the
gods
and that's a concept you even have in
Zoroastrianism which came after Hinduism
when there was a change cultural
religious change in Persia
right but they call it the yasna we call
it yajna they call it yasna but it's the
same thing they also have the same thing
so it's so fire worship seems to be
seems to be a practice that the Arya
people developed.
It wasn't there before us.
Okay.
Dark Knight says, "Why were Hindu social
reformers in the 19th century so opposed
to idol worship?" Brahmo samaj samaj and
many of them were against it.
You know the only
social reform that India needed in the
19th century was the eviction of the
foreign occupiers of India. That was the
only social reform India needed. India
was under brutal barbaric foreign
occupation. The only social reform
needed in India
was the eviction
of the foreign occupiers.
But then you had these reform movements
who wanted to reform Hinduism
and they were opposed to very central
concepts in in Hindu dharma
opposed to bhorti puja why
so I will not take any names of any
individuals because it will hurt
people's sentiment some people's
sentiments
so I will not take the names of these
various social so-called social
reformers but it always appeared to be
that they were somehow in some shape or
for or form aligned with British
interests,
right? I mean
who why do you have to propagate this
idea that mortuja is evil or bad? It is
some kind of a superstition or some kind
of defect. Why? Why do you want to
abrahamize
Hindu dharma? I I never I'm never able
to I never got it. Why?
Until I considered the possibility that
maybe some of these people or maybe they
were
aligned with
British interests
or other interests in some shape or
form. Okay. The only social reform India
needed was the eviction of the foreign
occupiers. That's all that was needed.
So yeah, deeply suspicious. That's what
that's what I'll say.
Okay,
Niraj Desai says why are places why why
are names of places like Wasco in Goa
not changed? A few years ago Oruranga or
the name of Orurangabad was changed to
Chhatrapati Shambhaji Nagar but there
are still many places named after
intruders after invaders after foreign
occupiers. Why is that?
Because India is still still deeply
colonized. India is still deeply
mentally colonized. You go to Vasco in
Goa. I mean I mean I have never been to
Wasco in Goa. I've never been to Goa.
>> So forget about Vasco as an as an
example. Let's take some other example.
There is a place called Muridabad
named after Murid Kuli Khan or
something.
Why do we have to name PE places after
the names of invaders?
And and and
who was the guy who destroyed Nalanda? I
think something is named after him too,
right? The the nearby railway station is
named after the guy who destroyed
Nalanda. What is the name? One second.
Uh
Baktiarpur, right? Baktiur.
Baktiarpur.
Right.
Named after
named after whom it's named after
Muhammad Ibin Bakti Gi
is known for destroying Nalandanda and
Vikram Shila and we have named a town
after this guy and we we still haven't
changed the name. I don't know why. So
this I suppose maybe the people who live
there are proud of being of the place
being called Baktiur possibly. I don't
I'm guessing.
So maybe it's that many of these places
that are named after foreign occupiers
and invaders and barbarians. Maybe the
people who live there may be proud of
the city being named after those people.
I don't know. India is still deeply
deeply mentally colonized.
We don't teach
in our education system what these
barbarians did to us. I've heard that
NCERT textbooks have changed kind of. Do
the NCERT textbooks now teach students
how the British systematically
engineered famines in India and killed
hundreds of millions of Indians?
I'm not sure they do. They're changing a
few things here and there and Indians
are like celebrating. Yes, we're good
now. No, you're not good. So
there
if you want to if you want to solve
these issues, you you to reform the
education system, which is nowhere near
happening. And that's why the names of
places are not changed. We still are
proud of the names of places named after
invaders. We we proud of it. It's very
sad but it is what it is. Yes.
Amisha says why did the industrial
revolution happen in Europe and not at
the time more developed
more developed civilizations like China,
India and Arabia. I'm not sure if Arabia
was a a developed civilization but China
and India certainly were. So why did
this industrial revolution happen in
Europe not China not India? H see the
industrial revolution is something that
happened in the mid 18th century right
and a bunch of conditions came together
to make it happen.
What
shaped [snorts]
what caused what precipitated the the
industrial revolution was a bunch of
factors like abundant energy,
access to big markets, um abundant
energy, abundant resources, access to
huge markets, uh institutions that that
that
allowed the the development of
technology and ideas, new new ideas that
bring that that gave rise to the
technologies, right?
So a bunch of things came together and
there these things did not exist in the
same place at the same time in India and
China or in the Islamic world at the
time. So first of all energy like I said
you needed access to abundant energy
which is coal. So if you look at England
for example, if you look at Belgium, if
you look at Germany, they had access to
abundant coal near the industrial
centers they were creating. Then they
had access to to resources that were
coming in from overseas colonies
especially England. They would bring in
resources, they would bring in materials
and then they would transform them into
finished products. Then they had access
to colonies. So the the British, they
had access to the Americas, they had
access to the Caribbean, they obviously
had access to India, the major crown
jewel of their empire. They had access
to resources that that came in from
Africa also, right? And various parts of
Asia. So these resources all came in
these raw materials they they they would
bring in from these parts of the world
and they would transform them into
finished products. Then they had this
capitalist culture, capitalist
structure. They had strong financial
institutions.
They had legal protection for for
private property. They were easily able
to mobilize capital through through
joint stock companies. They had
insurance. They had legislation that was
friendly to to investors and
entrepreneurs. So all these things made
it easy to mobilize the capital you
needed for factories, for
infrastructure, for mines, all of that.
Then one thing that you had in England
and some of these countries is that
you had high wages relative to the cost
of energy. Okay. So energy costs
whatever per unit whatever and compared
to that the cost of labor per unit is
pretty high. And that incentivized
machines that were laborsaving in
nature.
That's why these nations produced these
economically attractive laborsaving
machines. Automation,
right?
Then what you had in Europe was you had
many competing nations.
There's political fragmentation in
Europe. You don't have a single empire
in Europe. you had you had many
competing nations, many competing
states. So that created the incentive in
nations like England to innovate
rapidly on a war footing in technology,
in finance, in in warfare also, right?
Um and then you had in England the the
the tradition of piracy
when the Americas were being taken over
by the by the Spaniards and the English
were left behind. Queen uh Elizabeth,
she essentially supported piracy, state
sponsored piracy.
So you had that you so they were very
willing to cut corners and do things
that were illegal as per the rules-based
world order and the objective was to was
to win. So you had that and you had you
had the Elizabeth and age in England um
that was the precursor to the industrial
revolution that that supported science
and technology which was no longer
overtly religious um and that that's why
you had in England things like
scientific societies that came up patent
systems universities that were
increasingly open to physics to natural
philosophy and all of this then linked
the practical mechanics with theoretical
science and that gave rise is to
eventually the perfect conditions for
creating an industrial revolution
and because the European nations were
were so competitive
that's why they they sought to expand
territories elsewhere and that also gave
rise to the era of colonization of of
foreign occupation of the Americas of
Africa of India eventually various parts
of Asia and so on so all of these
factors came together and they do not we
do not have these factors in let's say
China or India
um all the factors at the same time in
the same place that's why you have this
industrial revolution in Europe and not
other places
says the exodus of Israelites from Egypt
the truth versus narrative so the
foundation story of Israel is that the
Israelite people were enslaved in Egypt
and then they were they were they were
they were they
They were they were freed by Moses who
took them to freedom. They crossed the
Red Sea because Moses parted the Red
Sea. They crossed the Red Sea and they
came into the Sinai Peninsula and they
spent decades wandering the Sinai
Peninsula and eventually uh populated
Israel. So that is the national
foundation story of Israel. Okay. Now
what's the truth is the question.
the truth. U first you you ask yourself,
do we have any archaeological evidence
of the presence of Jewish people in
ancient Egypt before let's say 1,00 BC?
Actually, you don't. There's no any
there's there's no hard unambiguous
archaeological evidence of any presence
of Israeli or or Jewish people in Egypt
before 1,00 [clears throat]
u BC. Uh you do have the the Hikos,
okay, the Hicks who were who invaded and
occupied Egypt for a century and a half.
The Hicks, okay, let's go to that. Uh
which I've spoken about in the past.
The Hixos, they uh ruled Egypt between
1630 and 1523. And some historians
interpret the Hixos as a Sematic people.
Okay, sematic people. Because Hixos had
war chariots,
they had curved double curved boughs.
They brought in new technology like the
axe and the ball.
And they had a storm god or a thunder
god.
They brought in horses.
But if you look at the characteristics
of the Hixos, they could very well also
be Arian people. And actually the the
they seem more like Arian people than
Semitic people, right? But the consensus
right now is that the Hixos were Semitic
people. But the Hixos were invaders and
rulers.
How would they be slaves? But the Hixos
eventually were defeated and went back.
But maybe some of them did not go back
and maybe they were enslaved. So that is
a very far-fetched interpretation. The
Hixos from the way I see it were not
Semitic. They were more of Indo-Iranian
or something because at the same time
you very very soon you have the Mitani
and the Hittite empires that come up
north of Sai in Anatolia which seem to
be to have the same culture as Hos. But
the mainstream consensus is that the
Hixos were sematic people. Maybe
Babylonian people. Maybe the god they
worshiped was was Bal, the storm god,
but not the the thunder god of the
Arians. Not that. So So if you were to
claim that the Hixos were related to the
Israel Israelite people and they were
enslaved, that is incredibly
far-fetched.
We also know that you had the Israeli
people
who who existed maybe around 1300 BC or
something in what is now Israel that
that region. So if they already existed
there, how do you have them enslaved in
Egypt? So it doesn't really add up. But
that doesn't mean it did not have
happen. Maybe a small number of Jewish
people were indeed possibly potentially
enslaved in Israel in in in Egypt. maybe
1500 BC or thereabouts and maybe they
they were able to escape eventually and
their story became the national founding
story of Israel
perhaps that is speculation but from an
from a from the perspective of hard
evidence we don't have any hard evidence
of u of Jewish people being enslaved in
Egypt there's no hard evidence it
doesn't mean that it did not happen but
there's no hard evidence
Okay. Uh, we still have more questions,
but we have gone way past two hours. So,
I will now end the Q&A. I I can take
some questions from the live chat
potentially.
Um, and I can see we have 19 super
chats. So, I'm going to have to take
those. [laughter]
19 super chats. So, let's go through the
super chats. Uh, please don't take any
more super chats because otherwise this
live stream will never end.
Um so VSVS thank you very much sir and
vss thank you very much for gifting
memberships I really appreciate that you
are very kind very grateful and uh yeah
now
Mr. Sid says, "What's the history and
the roots of Malayalis in Malalam?" The
Malali people in the Malam language I am
not very sure. I have not studied this
in any significant detail. What I know
is that the Mallayalam language is
pretty similar to Tamil. There are
definite connections between the
Mallayalam language and the Tamil
language. But malam has more Sanskrit
words than Tamil. Maybe 45% of
Mallayalam vocabulary will have its
origins in Sanskrit. Tamil maybe 30% 35%
maybe slightly less but what's the
origins I am not sure I have not studied
this in in any significant detail so uh
I can't answer
sorry about that shakshinat says um what
do you think of the India UAE deal
especially the civil nuclear agreement
for reactors that happened a few days
ago with the king of the UAE coming to
Delhi for only a few hours so I spoke
about this in detail a while ago I think
it's a redundant question but uh I think
it's a very interesting deal. Um the
contours, the parameters, the details of
the deal haven't been spelled out in
great detail, but we know that there is
a there is a potential
defense agreement between the two
nations. Um there is going to be more
cooperation in a variety of sectors
between the two nations. There is a
civil nuclear agreement of some kind.
What are the details? I'm still not 100%
clear, but we'll we'll wait for more
details to emerge. So overall, I think
this is fantastic. It's great that we
are deepening our cooperation with the
UAE, a like-minded nation, a very
friendly nation in the Gulf region, in
the West Asia region. Um, at least 40%
of the UAE's population is of Indian
origin. I'm not saying citizens, but
population. Um and what we are not
seeing behind the scenes I mean if you
are witnessing this it may look like
India and the UAE are coming together to
counter Saudi Arabia Pakistan but behind
the scenes
in the Saudi Arabia Pakistan
relationship there is also Turkey which
we don't which which is not that visible
and when it comes to India and UAE there
is Israel that's also on the same side.
So it's essentially India, Israel, UAE
on one side, Saudi Arabia, Pakistan,
Turkey on another another side.
So that's what's happening. You you're
kind of seeing a split of some kind. Um
and overall it's good for India. It's
good for India. It's good for the UAE.
It's good for the entire region overall.
ICMBBS says, "Is Donald J. Trump more
overt about US intentions or just
erratic?" He's not erratic. He knows
exactly what he's doing. There's a
there's a pattern to everything he's
doing. He's securing
America's energy interests. First of
all, Venezuela's energy interests, Iran
potentially is energy interests, right?
And by securing America's energy
interests and the global energy sources,
he's piling on the pressure on China
and all of that it fits fits a pattern.
He's putting more pressure on his his
vasals, his his allies, his his assets
in the EU and NATO. That also makes the
US more stronger. If he acquires
Greenland, it's better for the US.
Anyway, Denmark has no way of stopping
the US to do from doing it. You can't
have a power vacuum.
Um, so overall, he is strengthening the
American position in the world. He's
rewriting the rules of the game when it
comes to his vasals. He's telling them
now the rules have changed.
Um so he's not being erratic.
He's being very open about the US and
its status as an imperial power. Right?
So it's it's very clear that whatever
he's doing is all about making the
making the US more powerful. He knows
the Chinese are extremely wary of any
kind of military entanglement with the
US and he's going to take that and drive
home the advantage based on this
restraint that China has. So what he's
doing is great for the US actually.
[clears throat]
Jior TV says is Greenland being done
because the ice there is melting really
fast and an Arctic shipping lane is
emerging. What's happening? See if you
look at the Greenland region. Okay, I'm
not sure if the satellite images will
show us the situation, but let's let's
try. So, we're looking at the map of the
world. We Let's go all the way up north.
If you see between Russia and North
America, we have Greenland very clearly.
Now, if you look at the satellite image,
you will see if you zoom in,
this is a satellite image. Terrain.
Terrain.
What are we doing?
I'm not sure.
Okay. So, [snorts] it's icebound. This
entire region is very bigly very bigly
icebound. Okay. The thing is that as the
climate, as the global climate gets
warmer, you will find that you will have
the northern region becoming more
passible over the years, which means
that ships will be able to fly over
here. uh the ice will not be there all
year round and that will make this place
a contested region because there's a lot
of resources to be found in this region.
Oil, gas, natural resources, minerals,
what not? And Greenland is a big part of
that. Now, is the ice melting in
Greenland? It's not. Greenland has this
massive sheet of ice that's been there
for thousands of years because
Greenland, if you can't see the
topography over here, but it has these
mountains that are keeping all the
ancient ice uh stuck inside. It's see
ice sheets, how do they melt? They
essentially slide into into the ocean.
But when you have Greenland ringed with
mountains all over the place, the ice is
trapped inside. So it's very ancient ice
that's trapped inside and it's not
really melting really fast. But the the
overall northern Arctic region, it's
becoming more passible by more
traversible by by by ship as time goes
by. So as that passage these passages
open up there's going to be more
competition for for for primacy in this
region and that's why Trump wants to
grab Greenland right now. Makes sense.
Arctic ship in lanes. Yeah. That's
right. Absolutely.
Naven Johawan says Israel has the Samson
option as ultimate deterrence. Does
India have a comparable civilizational
a Mahakal doctrine or only regional
nuclear posture? We haven't communicated
any of this.
>> [clears throat]
>> The US has the mega Samson Samson
option. If there's a nuclear strike on
the US, the US will nuke every
significant country in the world
including India. Whether you've done
something or not doesn't matter. They're
going to nuke everybody. The isra has a
sen option in which it has a allegedly a
list of nations it will nuke if it is
going down in a nuclear strike. What
nations these are?
They know.
Uh does India have something to this?
Not that we have communicated. We
haven't communicated any such thing.
We probably have um assured retaliation.
If someone
launches a nuke at us and and you know
detonates a nuke on our territory, we're
going to nuke them back. That's the kind
of assurance we give. But we don't have
as far as I know a Samson option or
something Mahakal doctrine or whatever.
We have never communicated any such
thing.
Jor TV says, "I wanted to understand if
we are able to build our own fifth
generation combat aircraft, which is an
extreme extremely complex job, then why
don't we also work on basic logistics
aircrafts like the Embraer C 390? If
Brazil can do this, why can't we?" Well,
that's a great question. What is the
Embraer C3 C uh 390? Let's see.
Embryer
C390.
What is this? It is this transport
aircraft. Twin jet engine twin engine
jet powered military transport aircraft.
Medium-sized aircraft.
Why don't we build such aircraft? Why
don't why do we have to import
everything from elsewhere? Why doesn't
India have an industry that manufactures
aircraft of that are comparable to this?
The Americans have they make their own
aircraft all of all kinds. The Chinese
have repurposed Russian designs of
aircraft and they now manufacture their
own massive transport aircraft. The
Russians also do this. We simply import
everything. So we are in the process of
you know designing and building our
fifth generation combat aircraft. Sure
we know that it's a complex job but we
are we're going to get it done next
decade or so, right? But why don't we
build? Why don't we work on these
transport aircraft and all that? Why
not? I just don't know why.
Maybe it's a lack of ambition. Maybe
it's a lack of seriousness. Maybe we are
not a serious nation. Maybe our leaders
don't think it's important.
Why haven't we been doing this? The
Brazilians could do it.
Why? Why don't we do it? We are now kind
of getting a little serious. We we are
going to build the super sukoy in India.
Uh super sukoy. What is that?
Super
Sukcoy
100.
Super Sukoy 100 which is the the SJ 100,
right? It's a it's it's a civilian
transport aircraft. Medium-sized. It can
carry maybe a 100 people. And we're
going to be we're going to set up
production lines for this in India
eventually some someday in the future.
Yeah.
But why don't we build transport
aircraft? We should, right? We should
build transport aircraft. We should
build strategic bombers.
We've never even attempted this. It
tells you our leadership in the past
decades has never
considered this to be important. Is it
not important? It is super important. So
it's it's lack of quality leadership,
lack of ambition, lack of seriousness.
I don't have any other answer. We should
have all this in India. We should be
building our own aircraft of all kinds.
But we're not. Of course, in recent
times, we have made progress. We have
the the fighter plane. Various
iterations are being worked upon. We are
working on the AMCA. We also have uh the
light combat helicopter. We also have
the other helicopter. So we are now
taking it seriously and we are slowly
starting to build various kinds of
aircraft
but this I don't see that happening
right now. Maybe we should right maybe
we should
not maybe we definitely should. Aayush
Gupta says the best comment is by Musk.
It's peace not peace. Did he say that?
That's an interesting comment.
Okay. Died in plane crush says
SH
is
okay. Air pollution in Northern India.
Yeah, the the air quality is terrible in
northern India. I'm not sure what it is
right now. I was in Delhi about a week
ago. It was absolutely terrible.
Um obviously it will affect people's
lungs. The kind of air pollution you
have it's like people are smoking a
cigarette a minute that sort of thing. I
mean you can see the smoke in the air
visible. Uh will this affect the
performance of armed forces personnel?
Maybe not.
Nothing significant I suppose. You know
when people spend their entire lives in
northern India
obviously this is this is a phenomenon
that's more recent 20 years ago you do
not have the same kind of air pollution
that we have right now obviously it's
going to have some kind of effect on
your overall performance as a human
being if you're a soldier it may perhaps
decrease your performance by one or two%
perhaps maybe [snorts] even 5% but
overall it makes no doesn't probably
doesn't make a significant impact
but obviously I I agree with you that
this needs to be addressed. You kind of
have people living in gas chambers. It's
terrible. Terrible. So, it needs to be
addressed.
Uh had to write in Hindi as YouTube
won't allow otherwise. Well, that's very
interesting. YouTube won't allow it
unless you write in Hindi. Okay.
[laughter]
All right. Chirajad says, "Why did
Brnavv see socialism with the human face
as a threat to the Soviet block and
which ultimately led to the crushing of
the Prague spring?"
socialism of the human face. Crushing of
the Prague Spring. See the crushing of
the Prague Spring was what? 1960
something 50.
Let me just check out the date. Crushing
60 something. Crushing.
Crushing of Prague Spring.
Crushing. Yeah. 68.
Yeah. So they invaded Czechoslovakia and
ended the Prague Spring. Czechoslovakia
was was
um part of the Warso packed grouping of
nations, right? Um the Soviet block.
So there was this demand for freedom for
for for democracy and so on in
Czechoslovakia. The Soviet Union was
okay with everything as long as there
was no question of questioning the
supremacy of the USSR. And if that comes
under threat then obviously you send in
tanks, right? So it was not that
socialism with a human face was a threat
to the Soviet block.
The threat to the Soviet block was that
certain nations would potentially see
this as a weakness and they may try to
secede from the Soviet block and maybe
become part of the western block. That
obviously is was intolerable and that's
why the Soviets when they saw that there
was a revolt
and the revolters demanded freedom from
the USSR that's when you had to send in
tanks as simple as that. DH Kotwani is a
new member. Thank you very much sir.
Thank you very much and welcome to the
membership of the channel.
Thank you. Brown Leprechaun says,
"Assuming the painter didn't die in
1945, why did the Americans allow him to
exist?
Why would the Americans allow the
painter to exist?" Well, the painter, if
he did exist, he would have not if he if
he did continue existing, let's say
hypothetically the painter did not die
in 45 and maybe hypothetically he went
and settled down in South America
perhaps somewhere. Uh Adolf Iikman was
found in Argentina.
Apparently, Mangalia was also found in
Argentina, but he was never never
captured by the Israelis.
So maybe many of these ex-Nazis had
settled in South America, maybe
Argentina. And hypothetically, if the
painter had also settled there, why
would the Americans allow him to exist?
Well, hypothetically, if this was true,
the painter would not have posed any
more threat to the US.
Then maybe
first of all he didn't pose any threat
when Shinkis Khan
decided that he will not cross the Indis
river in pursuit of Jalaludin
in 1221 or wherever it was
AD it's because Jalodin had lost his
army jingishan destroyed his army and
Jaladin no longer posed a threat so let
him go into India let him go to Deli and
seek refuge in Iltmish's court. He no
longer poses a threat. He's no longer
significant. Let him go. That was
Chingish Khan's logic. So maybe the
Americans may have employed a similar
logic if the painter hypothetically had
settled in South America. Maybe that's
that's one hypothetical reason why the
Americans may have allowed him to exist.
Maybe
could he provide some services to them
like the some of the Nazis did because
some Nazis were elevated to very high
positions by the Americans. Um
NATO chief of staff staff what was what
was his name? U
NATO commander
Nazi who was Adolf Hoisinger.
Adolf Hoisinger right
there. We have this guy.
So
he What was his NATO designation? NATO
chief of staff. Yeah. So the Americans
were okay with Nazis as long as they
were useful. And maybe maybe the painter
maybe may not have been useful, but
maybe he did not pose any threat. Uh,
it's only speculation. Can't really say.
NPS says, "How Spain successfully
reclaimed their Christian identity after
Islamic rule ended Spaniards made
churches again after destroy destroying
Islamic structures. Did they face any
resistance like we see in India?
I'm not sure what resistance we see in
India, but uh, okay. the
Spain reclaiming its Christian identity
and expelling the North African Moors
and the Arabs. It's called the
reconista, the reconquest of Spain from
the foreigners. Okay. So, Islamic rule
did not end overnight. It was a long
long long process of several centuries.
Reconista, how many centuries did it
lasted? Several centuries, maybe seven
centuries.
Reconista,
how many centuries? many years.
Uh so it's like several centuries. See
718 to 1492 almost 700 800 years. The
Spaniards fought for almost 8 centuries
to finally fully evict the foreigners
from their their land. Okay. It was a
long long long arduous struggle almost
800 years. It's not like they fought
over a weekend and then won. 800 years
they fought almost that's how they were
able to finally successfully reclaim
their their land and eject the Arabs and
the Moors from Spain they faced
tremendous resistance obviously if it
lasted 800 years almost right so there
are the deal was a long long long
struggle for the Spaniards
Shashank says it seems global deterrence
moved from military force to controlling
chips energy social media why our
nations
still planning for 20th century wars
because 20th century wars see we not no
one's planning for 20th century wars
people are planning for 21st century
wars
I mean Ukraine is happening right it's
still a war whether we have chips energy
social media Ukraine war is still
happening if China tries to take tries
to take Taiwan it won't take Taiwan with
social media or chips or energy but
energy will play a factor will play a
role it will be a big factor if China
doesn't have sufficient energy energy
oil and gas then it won't be able to
invade Taiwan.
When it comes to chips, chips are the
foundation of data and AI, right? Chips
are behind all this, not data, but AI.
The nation with the best AI will have
the best strategies and tactics. It'll
be able to adapt in real time to
changing and evolving battle conditions.
But at the end of the day, a war is
fought through kinetic means, not
through social media and energy and
chips. Energy is obviously there. You
can't fight a war without energy
resources.
And you will fight a better war if you
have the better AI,
right? And you can fight a better war if
you can de demoralize the population of
the inomination through social media
manipulation. So everything is inter
integrated now. But wars are still
fought through chinetic means through
bombs. Now we have drones.
Now you're going to have autonomous
uh elements in warfare, automated uh
elements like drone warfare. Sometimes a
drone can be completely autonomous. Uh
so we are now planning for 21st century
scenarios where everything is
integrated. cyber warfare, AI,
social media, energy, chips,
space,
all of this comes together and kinetic
means,
right? So if you so India also has
adopted, right? When you saw operation
Synindur, you had some AI, you had
automation for sure, you had drones.
India excelled in drones, drone warfare,
the aerial war. So it's not like we are
still planning for 20th century wars and
the cautionary message you are sending
here is very well received.
So nations that plan that that fail to
adapt
to the evolving situation of the 20th
century and still keep on planning for
20th century wars they're going to fail.
So if you have a nation whose air force
still wants to be the best air force in
dog fighting what that is 20th century
warfare. Nobody does dog fighting today.
Today the the today you take out the
adversaries assets from 100 kilometers
away. There's no dog fighting anymore.
That's fifth generation warfare. Right.
In terms of aerial warfare. So you are
right to caution to to put in this word
of caution that we can't plan for 20th
century wars. We have to adapt to the
21st century scenario where everything
is integrated.
Unamalai says can anyone file a case in
Supreme Court to make Indian temples
come out of the control of the Indian
government? Temple money is getting
lost. I don't understand I don't know
how it is done whether this can work or
not and I anyway don't I don't comment
about internal matters in India. I talk
about geopolitics history and science.
This is internal affairs in India. I
don't know how the legal system works
whether this will work or not. So I
can't say sorry.
[laughter] Excuse me. Pre
LTP says, "Why tech billiondoll
investment in Greenland?"
I'm not aware of tech billion dollar
investment in Greenland. I'm not aware.
I'll have to look into it. I don't
really know at this point in time.
Sahil says, "I am getting a bit
depressed on will we ever reach European
level of quality of life and urban
infrastructure and cleanliness in India
in our lifetimes."
Um hopefully we do hopefully we do uh a
lot will have to change for that to
happen. India will have to become a you
know a middle income nation for us to
reach the quality of life and also we'll
have to deal with certain internal
structural issues and we'll have to
bring in some reforms. It certainly is
possible. Um if India keeps growing at
the current rate 6 7 8% per year for the
next 20 years we're going to reach the
per capita GDP of a middle income
nation.
And if if we reach there then we should
reasonably it would be reasonable for us
to expect those standards but for those
standards to happen even if you're a
middle incumbent but let's say if you
allegedly have corruption all over the
place and so on then you will never
improve into the standards. So those
reformative actions will have to be
taken
uh it is certainly possible with the
right leadership. So
possible is it? It certainly is possible
but it will depend on the kind of
leadership that we have over the next 20
years.
So let's be optimistic. All right. Jazz
1993 forever says, "Be watching your
videos since 2021. I always recommend
your videos to my friends and family
members cuz you explain in simple terms
which is easy to understand. Please do a
meet up in Mumbai at some place of for
your subscribers. First of all, thank
you so much. Thank you so much for
having been a viewer since 2021 and
being so kind as to recommend uh my
videos to friends and family. Thank you
so much. I try my best to keep things as
simple as possible. You can explain
things in a complicated way if you want
to start if you want to sound smart and
intelligent and impress everybody, but
then you defeat the purpose of what
you're trying to do. So, I try to keep
it as simple as possible and that's
that's what I've striven to do over the
past four or so years. So thank you so
much. Uh meet up in Mumbai at some place
for my sub subscribers.
Okay, I will consider that. Um
it certainly can be planned and
organized I suppose. So yeah, thank you
for the suggestion. I will uh consider
that seriously. Thank you. Feels strong
man says you've mentioned that India
should keep quiet and keep working
towards 10 trillion dollar economy and
currently we we are boastful with
proclamation of vixit bharat but we need
positive perception plus motivation plus
fdi to combat global anti-India
sentiment. No oh yes yes we should
portray India correctly as a very
attractive destination for investment.
We should also say that we are improving
on various parameters.
right that India is becoming more vixit
see look at the infrastructure we're
building look at the roads we're
building look at the railway network
we're building
look at the UPI that is so successful
talk about all these things but don't
talk about we are becoming a superpower
vishwaguru and look at our military
capabilities and all that you keep quiet
you should know what you should talk
about and you should know what you keep
quiet about don't boast about us
becoming a superpower like so many
Indians do
it did that we will beat you, we'll
defeat Pakistan is nothing and Saudi
Arabia is nothing and Turkey is nothing
and we'll defeat you and all the just
keep quiet all these things right
so obviously we have to portray India as
a good destination for investment good
destination for tourism a cultural you
know superpower and so on but let's keep
quiet about whatever else right let's
not start getting ahead of ourselves
okay godliness says there are chatters
that Iran may now have the nuclear bomb.
What's my view? And I also know for
geopolitics, we need Iran, but what that
Islamist is doing on the street with his
own people is disgusting. What is that
Islamist doing on his streets with his
own people? Whatever you think is
happening, it's coming from Western
media.
I was recently on a on on a podcast,
okay, as a guest and the host tells me
Iran in Iran 12,000 people have died. I
said, "What's your evidence? You're a
journalist. You're claiming 12,000
people have died. What's the evidence
that 12,000 people have died? If you
make a claim as a journalist, you need
to have some evidence to back it up. Do
you have people on the ground who have
counted the 12,000 dead?
Do you have actual video or photographic
evidence of 12,000 people dead?
or the western media that's reporting
this do they have evidence of this on
what basis are these numbers been thrown
out and there's no answer to it
so I don't know see in India the Indian
media just repeats the talking points of
the west of the western media there is
no original reporting in India nothing
and that's why Indians simply believe
whatever the west is telling them that
so many thousands of people have been
killed in Iran by the Islamist regime
there is zero evidence to back it up We
see some videos of violence. We see some
people who are unfortunately deceased
and all that, but it's not 12,000. We
see some videos of people firing at
crowds. Who are those people?
Are they Iranian government forces in
plain clothes or are they foreign agents
in plain clothes?
We don't know. So, how can you come to
the conclusion
that so and so is happening in Iran
because the BBC is saying it or CNN is
saying it or whatever? Oh, I mean have
some sense,
use some critical thinking, not simply
blindly believe what the media tells
you. Western media
now about Iran having the nuclear bomb
potentially. It may I have been saying
this for like two years at least that
Iran definitely will have sufficient
file material
weapons grade uranium potentially for a
few nuclear bombs maybe five maybe 510
they may have it
but they have been very scared to
operationalize the nuclear deterrent
haven't they to operationalize a nuclear
deterrent you need to conduct at least
one nuclear test
when that is done you are now
demonstrated nuclear power. Iran has
never done that. Too scared,
right? And see where they are today.
Um,
it's possible they may have it. But if
they want to be a credible nuclear power
and to deter regime change and what not,
they will need to well, unfortunately
demonstrate they have one by doing at
least one nuclear test.
Godliness says the big eagle can use
Kurish people for fighting against the
barbarians of ISIS. But now those who
saved us all from jihad are left to die.
See that's that's the thing. The world
isn't a fair place
if you will allow yourself to be used as
a pawn by a foreign power.
Pawns are disposable pieces.
Right? Of course, the Kurdish people
desire to they seek to have their own
homeland. No one's going to give them a
homeland of their own,
right? So sometimes they'll be used to
fight ISIS then next ISIS will be will
will be used to fight the Kurds and so
on. That is the way the big powers the
western powers have always played.
That's the game they've always played.
Take one group and make make them fight
another. Then next then a few months
later the one you're fighting against
now they become your guy and you'll make
them fight the other guy. That's how the
game of
thrones
the game of geopolitics has been played
by the west for decades for centuries.
It's cruel. It's heartless.
It is what it is. That's how it goes.
Two idiot NRIs
says H chiefs are saying that they just
MK2 rollout already happened. What does
a non-public roll out even mean since
it's not a taxi trial? I have no idea
really. Um
they just MK2 roll out really
just MK2 roll out really has it
happened? They just MK2 advances towards
first flight as former D former D or
something. Um what's it say?
Former DRDO joint director confirms roll
out in internal testing.
So the MK2 program has quietly test
crossed the Malaysian milestone. The
aircraft's rollout already completed and
internal trials are now in process
progress.
This confirmation has come from joint
director at the DRDO who revealed the
development while speaking to news one
and so on and so forth. the focus is now
shifted entirely to internal ground in
system trials and so on. Um, okay. The
Okay, maybe it's a good thing. Uh,
non-public roll out. Maybe a rollout
doesn't have to be public, I suppose.
Um, it's okay if they do this behind
closed doors. That's all right. I'm I am
not opposed to that. Why does everything
have to be public? When India developed
nuclear weapons, did we make it public?
Joint public roll out live telecast
of the first nuclear test? No, it's not
like that. It's it's fine. Um, if the
rollout has already happened, that's
fantastic.
Um, that's all I can say about this. I
am not opposed to a non-public
uh roll out. I'm not opposed to that.
I'm not sure is it it's not a taxi trial
yet. So, when it's not public, you don't
know exactly what's happened, but looks
like there is progress and I'm that that
pleases me. That's all I can say at this
time. Humanity survives says how do you
see the world in 2050? I see multiple
scenarios. One scenario is US primacy.
The US is the supreme superpower who
rules everybody. Second is maybe you
have US versus RAIC,
Russia, India, China. That's a very
unlikely scenario but that's one
definitely nonzero probability scenario.
Third
scenario is maybe
maybe multipolar world. US is no longer
that
powerful and China, India, Russia and
maybe maybe France also are reasonably
powerful. Maybe NATO has broken up. Lots
of possibilities. The last thing I want
to see is nuclear war or third world war
or something. Um but the most likely
scenario is that the US is going to be
the most powerful nation in 2050. Most
likely scenario is that.
Uh Buddha says why is Indra dominant
over Vishnu and the Rig Veeda?
I don't have an answer. I I'm not not an
expert in this matter. Sorry.
Dir Kamat says why for the past 1,000
plus years we have Indians been behind
in behind competitors in terms of
strategic thinking, ambition and
technology and being reactive not
proactive. Is this a mentality or
ideology issue? See look when you come
under foreign occupation this is what
happens. The simple answer to your
question is that we were under foreign
occupation.
Starting from the northern part of India
about 1,000 years ago slowly gradually
descending
southwards.
Okay. For the longest time for from
about 700 something AD all the way to
about 1400s we fought we resisted but
eventually we came under full foreign
occupation and when you come under
foreign occupation and when the
foreigners disrupt your systems
dismantle your civilization bring in
foreign education, foreign bureaucracy,
foreign foreign institutions, foreign
language.
They mess with your minds and after you
become independent, your leaders
continue to the same system of that the
foreign occupants brought in, you're
going to become a nation that is not the
most ambitious, most
equipped to succeed. So you become
reactive, not proactive. You bring in
things like a hinsa. You start woriing a
hinsa. So what what do you expect? Do
you accept expect a nation to be react
proactive when it when it worships a
hinsa?
Right? When you don't teach the the
truth about what happened in the past
thousand years, even the past 250 years,
what the British did, you don't teach
them. You still portray the British as
as as glorious social reformers for
India who and all that. So, so what do
you expect?
It's not a mentality or ideology issue.
It's a leadership issue. Actually,
it's now a leadership issue.
Chattania on Texas says recently Trump
officially cons confirmed that the US
has directed energy weapons which was
used in Venezuela allegedly and that
that they are scaling them eventually
won't the same weapons end up in the
hands of terrorists Pakistan well
they'll end up in the hands of
terrorists if the Americans give them to
terrorists the Americans deal with
various kinds of terrorists they have
ISIS on their side you know uh Al Gulani
the so-called president of Syria is an
ISIS terrorist he is a US ally Uh
Pakistan is a terrorist nation. The
Americans are very favorable towards
Pakistan right now and they've been so
since the 1980s. So if the Americans
hand over these weapons to terrorists,
then they will end up in the hands of
terrorists such as Pakistan. It's
entirely the choice of the US. So yeah,
any weapon that the US has if they want
to give it to Pakistan, the Pakistanis
will have it. Most likely the Pakistani
nuclear deterrent is most likely
American warheads. I don't think it's
Pakistani warheads. Otherwise, how do
you control Pakistan? So if the
Americans give it to terrorists, the
terrorists will have those. Dir Kamat
says, "How then were Jews, a smaller
group than Kurds, able to get their own
homeland?" Unlike Kurds, do Kurds
constitute a very major, powerful,
prosperous, rich ethnic group in the US?
The Kurds do not. Are Kurds all across
the US government in positions of power?
The Kurds are not. That's the answer to
your question, sir. That's the answer to
your question. The Jews, they ensured
that they became wealthy and powerful
and they occupied multiple positions of
power throughout Europe and now in the
US. Is there something wrong in doing
that? No. They are really good at that.
That's admirable. It's an admirable
quality. The Indians haven't done that.
The Kurds haven't done that. So that's
where we are.
Ankita G. Ankita says, "What's your
opinion about Mr. Trump's inviting Prime
Minister Modi to join the board of
peace? How should India respond?"
According to me to to me,
according to me, India should neither
accept nor deny no nor reject this
proposal. India should ignore this
proposal. This board of peace is a
circus. If you see the the nations that
have joined the board of peace, it's a
bunch of nations who who are united by
the common purpose of wanting to please
Mr. Trump. Do you want do does India
want to be in the same position as
Pakistan? Pakistan is a honored member
of the board of peace.
Do you want to be in the in in the same
board as Pakistan? Israel hasn't joined.
Russia hasn't joined. China hasn't
joined. No self-respecting nation has
joined.
And if India joins the board of peace
and Mr. Trump convenes a summit meeting
of the board of peace, then he will play
he will pull some Trump some some stunt
on Mr. Modi. He'll try and make Mr. Modi
come and shake hands with Mr. Sharif.
Does Mr. Modi want to be in the same
room as Mr. Sharif? I don't think so. At
this point in time, Mr. Modi should not
even be in the same room as Mr. Trump
because Mr. Trump is is prone to
humiliating various world leaders and
countries. My opinion is that India
should stay far away from the so-called
board of peace. That's my opinion. And
that brings me to the end to the
conclusion of this live stream. We have
taken a lot of questions and I thank you
all my dear friends my dear friends for
these questions for all the questions.
And so this brings me to the end of
today's live stream. Thank you very
much. I look forward to seeing you
tomorrow. We're going to do a live
stream all based on super chats
tomorrow. Ask me anything you want. I'll
take your questions there tomorrow.
Until then, keep learning, keep qu
asking questions, keep raising your
standards. I'll see you tomorrow. Thank
you everyone. Good night, good day. See
you soon. See you tomorrow. Bye-bye.